That area's off limits.
It's got to be a Russian sub.
The readings aren't typical
of their nuclear vessels, sir.
Something weird is going on.
Hmm.
Try to make contact!
They might be in trouble.
Intruder aboard. Dead ahead. Inside.
Open the hatch.
What's that? A woman?
Get them up, honey.
Nighty-night.
One year from now,
you will become an army of living dead
to serve The Mandarin.
Hasta la vista, Boris.
Sorry to hypnotize and run.
I'm out of here.
Stop fighting it, Tony.
Come on, work into the pain.
Push, Tony! Harder!
Boy, is that all you've got?
Didn't anyone ever tell
you you're hard to resist?
Never try to snow
your physical therapist.
Now, good, lean on me,
point your toes and kick like crazy!
Come on, Tony, faster!
Whoa, man!
My job description didn't say anything
about getting spritzed by the boss.
March 11th, 3:00 P.M.
Hyper Tech seminar, remember?
I should give you a raise
for getting me out of
this torture chamber, Jim.
What is that?
It's a Code Ten alarm!
Hang on!
Come to papa.
Your hand, Whirlwind! Up, Knightwing!
Whirlwind and Dreadknight!
Veronica!
All right,
but she could have been killed.
They tried to break into the Armory
but they tripped all the alarms.
A direct assault on the
Armory in broad daylight?
That isn't The Mandarin's usual style.
Secure the area and clean up. We
don't want this leaking to the press.
I'm on it.
Double Armory security.
If The Mandarin gets the
secret for my armor for his army,
no one will be able to stop him.
They come!
Quickly.
They'll
never miss one microchip
when so many were
destroyed in the fire.
Yes.
This enables me to synchronize
with the device Hypnotia
planted on the submarine.
The fools think your
raid was a failure,
but in exactly one year,
I shall have the means
to destroy Iron Man.
That's a long time to
wait for vengeance, Mandarin.
I'd wait for eternity to
crush the only one who stands
between me and world domination!
It's been nearly a
year since The Mandarin bombed out
trying to get in here.
Think he's lost interest?
No way. It's not like him
to give up after one attempt.
Admiral Harold Younger, Tone.
He's got a job for Stark Enterprises.
Mr. Stark. The White House
wants you in on Operation Prometheus.
On March 11 last year,
the Prometheus, a Russian nuclear sub,
vanished off the coast of Norway.
Our task force just pinpointed
an area off the coast of Scotland
where we think the tides took her.
Mr. Stark, whatever is in that sub
may have the power
to destroy life on Earth.
A crewman on a British
frigate was taping his shipmates
just as this tanker passed
somewhere over the Prometheus.
It's as you feared. They know.
I fear nothing, Hypnotia,
but Tony Stark shall
not ruin our master plan.
I must inform The Mandarin at once.
What about my ride,
you horrible little troll?
You did
well to inform me, Modok.
Almost time.
Now nothing will interfere
with our rendezvous with destiny!
Tell that to Iron Man!
Tony Stark is sure
to send him to investigate.
Then we must be sure he has company.
Dreadknight! Blacklash!
Grey Gargoyle! Whirlwind!
Blizzard!
I have a mission for you. But first,
come forward, Blizzard.
What's the problem? I've been loyal!
Loyal, yes.
Intelligent, no!
When you carelessly created
a Fast Freeze to cool your drink,
you killed my begonias!
Unforgivable!
But I shall spare you,
because I am merciful.
Now go to the garden
and start fertilizing!
As you command.
On to the submarine Prometheus!
You shall provide a suitable
welcome for our iron-domed friend!
Nothing can stop The Mandarin!
The Prometheus vanished March 11,
the same day The
Mandarin hit the Armory.
You need to change to Undersea
Armor when you get there.
Now how are you gonna
handle that alone?
I won't be alone.
Meet IRVING!
Irving? Irving who?
My new invention. IRVING stands for
In-flight Refit Vehicle with Interactive
Neuromimetic Gear. I-R-V-I-N-G.
Powering up!
I still don't like it, Tone.
Thrusters on. Lift-off!
Onboard navigation
locked on destination,
and I'm avoiding civilian
and military air corridors.
Activating video.
You're
coming in loud and clear.
Piece of cake, Jimbo.
This is Reginald Dimpton at the
British end of the new Hammer Tunnel
which will link England to Belgium.
And now, the man who built
this engineering marvel...
Where's Iron Man?
Put Iron Man back on!
- Who's messing with the remote?
- Where is he?
Take it easy.
I was just looking for a ball game.
...Justin Hammer.
Thank you, Reg.
I'll cut the ribbon,
officially opening my tunnel,
when Big Ben strikes high noon.
We now return you to
our regular programming.
What's the story, I.M.?
I'm off the Scottish coast.
Readings indicate the Prometheus
is 81.3 fathoms below target scan.
Changing to Undersea Armor.
Now, IRVING.
Now let's find Prometheus!
After you, IRVING.
Coordinates established. Looks
like IRVING's picked up the scent.
I'm getting unusually strong energy
readings, but they aren't nuclear.
In fact, they seem to
be some new form of energy.
Looks peaceful enough.
No sensor warnings. And yet...
It's probably just this ghoulish
setting that's making me jumpy.
Closer.
Just a little closer.
Good-bye, Rust Bucket!
Ambush! Armor up!
War Machine!
Iron Man needs us. Now, Century!
By the power of my battle staff,
I bend time and space.
Fan out and find him!
I have anticipated everything,
as usual.
I have summoned the
alien dragon Fin Fang Foom!
Satisfactory.
My echo scanner
says Iron Man just took a laser hit
and the cyber feedback
reached his brain!
If we don't find him fast,
his mind will incinerate.
Fin Fang Foom!
Iron Man!
Century! Secure the perimeter
and prepare for an enemy attack!
We've got to get
him back to the Armory.
How you feeling?
Lousy.
I think I've almost
figured something out.
It was no problem until Fin Fang Foom
played Fangs for the
Memory on my cranium.
But none of the bad
guys were around when we showed up.
The Mandarin only
brings the dragon in on big deals.
Why would he do that
and then call him off?
Like, first they wanted to bust
your chops for checking out the sub,
and later they could care less.
Jim! "First" and "later."
"First" and "later" define time!
Something had to be happening
aboard the Prometheus.
When its time was up, The Mandarin
no longer had a reason to defend it!
March 11. There has to
be a link to this date. But what?
IRVING! I wondered
what happened to you.
That's it! Way to go, IRVING!
Now I know what this is all about!
If I'm right,
we haven't a minute to spare!
But you need rest... Later, Jim!
Now is the time for Iron Man!
And it's high noon here in London
as the world waits eagerly
for the opening of Hammer Tunnel.
The sequence is complete.
The world shall be mine!
This activates the sleeping
crew of the submarine.
Awake, my children. Awake!
The time has come to
serve your master. Now!
It took a year to
transform the Russian sailors
into unstoppable radioactive zombies.
- Serve master.
Serve master. Serve master.
The Mandarin
arranged for the sinking
of the Prometheus a year ago
and planted some sort
of bio-conversion device.
It extracted radical
iodine ions from sea water
and radioactively bonded them to
the normal body cells of the sailors.
It took twelve months to
transform them into zombie warriors.
Shouldn't you cut the ribbon?
Yes.
That would be a very good idea.
If The Mandarin's
zombies get loose,
their radioactivity
will contaminate millions,
and give The Mandarin a
vast slave army of the undead.
But that's not going to happen.
No! It's not possible!
Iron Man is here!
- Serve master.
Serve master. Serve master.
This is no way to treat a lady,
my pumpkin.
Especially your friend.
Here, that's too heavy for you.
I've got an idea!
Life support, adapt for
short-term underwater capability!
A year
of planning destroyed!
You'll pay for your bungling!
I haven't failed yet!
I've called in the most powerful
and destructive cyber-organism
in the universe.
Once unleashed, his ferocity
and strength are unstoppable!
You don't mean...
Not...
Yes!
Titanium Man! I thought
we finished him off at Magnitogorsk!
If we don't stop him...
We must stop him!
It's time to iron things out!
Quick! Before his
servo-stabilizers reset!
Nothing like asphalt
for gift-wrapping.
I think we better mark this
package "Do not open until Christmas
"in the year 3000."
Now!
Well, I guess that wraps things up.
One thing more.
The Russian sailors were innocent
victims of The Mandarin's scheme.
They must be redeemed.
Let their lives be as they were
before they served
aboard the Prometheus,
so justice is satisfied.
No.
No!