[HEAVY DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Many years ago, in
the realm of Apollyon,
past the garden
of four rivers,
and in the region of Abaddan,
there stood an old city.
Its name in the ancient
tongue was Noit Curtsed.
But time and speech
and a brilliant mind
named Lux soon set upon the
more pleasant name
of Not Cursed.
Though some would have
thought it wishful thinking,
for the city was indeed
cursed with perpetual decay,
leaving the
inhabitants no choice
but to labor perpetually
for the very sake
of their existence.
Years, decades, and centuries
passed, and the city
grew in number and labor.
Ruling over it were
the Supervisors,
descendants of Lux.
Brilliant organizers, they
kept the city in existence
by the oversight of endless
shifts and schedules.
Obstinate Heady.
Next.
Christian Pilgrim.
[CHRISTIAN SIGHS]
[GASP]
Oh!
Work was paramount, which is
why such a commotion resulted
one day when it was
discovered that--
A man has gone missing!
What?
Stand back, now.
[THUD]
Once more and--
[CRASH]
[SOFT MUSIC]
Whoa.
Oh, my.
Tear it all down, and burn it.
All of it.
Hurry up, now.
Supervisor 6 will
be here any minute.
And I'd be very
careful if I were you.
You want to avoid
any contamination.
[SOFT MUSIC]
So, that's him.
Right, you are.
Faithful Pathfinder.
Yeesh.
What a madman.
[SOFT MUSIC]
[CHRISTIAN SIGHS]
Well, you can't really
blame a man for dreaming,
can you, Obstinate?
Even if he is a madman.
Was a madman.
Only a madman would
be foolish enough
to venture beyond the borders.
Nothing good ever comes
from veering from the rules,
I always say.
Nothing at all.
Beyond the borders?
Is that where he went?
Yes.
And everyone knows
there's nothing
but death beyond the borders.
Isn't that right, uh--
what is your name?
Christian, Supervisor.
I mean, Christian.
You're the
supervisor, obviously.
And you don't want to catch
the same thing Faithful
Pathfinder did, do you?
Whatever it is that drove
him to this deviation.
No.
No, surely not.
Of course not.
Never.
No.
Good.
Do not fail to collect
every last scrap of paper.
Every sketch, any notes.
And you.
Yes, my superior?
I have a task for you.
Right away, my superior.
[LAUGH]
[GENTLE MUSIC]
[INSECTS CHIRPING]
[WHOOSHING]
[EXPLOSION]
[GASPING]
[SOFT MUSIC]
[DOOR CREAKS]
What was Faithful Pathfinder
thinking, I wonder?
It has been said that no
one just finds the Book,
but, rather, the
Book finds them.
And so it happened that
Christian began to read.
And read.
Unable to pry himself
from its pages,
he read the Book all through
the night and all the next day
and the day after that.
And the more he read, the
more his concern for right
things grew until they
became, as it were,
a great burden to him.
Christian read about things
he had never imagined,
about kindnesses he had
never known existed,
about wrongful things that
needed to be put right,
about the origins of his
city, and about a coming--
War?!
We have to get
out, Christiana.
It says so in this, and
I believe it in here.
And the war will
destroy the entire city?
So we must flee
and get to the--
Celestial City,
the City of Light.
The City of--
[LAUGH]
It's a book, Christian.
If you'd only read it,
you would understand.
It all makes-- [GROANS]
Sense?
You're asking me
and the children
to follow you
beyond the borders?
[SOB]
No, Christian.
It doesn't make sense.
None at all.
Ever since you started reading
that Book a few days ago,
you have gone on and on
and on like some lunatic.
"The city is going to be
destroyed. The city is
going up in flames."
It's hard for me
and for the children
to see you in
this sorry state,
all bent over and--
It's this weight.
Weight?
What weight, Christian?
You've gone to nothing
but skin and bones.
The more I read, the
more it weighs on me.
Don't you see?
Oh, Christian.
I know.
This all seems crazy.
I do.
But I love you.
And--and I only want what
is best for us all.
If the city is destroyed--
Oh.
If the city is
destroyed, I don't
want you, the children,
or anyone else
for that matter
to perish with it.
I love you, Christiana.
[SOFT MUSIC]
Then, choose.
What?
Choose, Christian.
The children, I, we can't take
seeing you like this day in
and day out.
You're going to have to
choose what you want to do.
Stay here with us or leave.
Because we're not
going with you.
We're not.
[DOOR CREAKS OPEN]
[DOOR SHUTS]
[GENTLE MUSIC]
[SIGH]
[FOOTSTEPS]
My superior.
Any signs?
Signs?
Oh, lots.
Why, there's one
right here, you see.
Of the missing man, you fool.
Oh!
Oh, oh, yes, yes.
Of course.
Well, uh, yes and no.
Yes and no?
We followed his footsteps
beyond the borders,
you see, to, um, to the
Swamp of Despondency.
So that's where he ended up.
[LAUGHS] The swamp.
Well, that's where the, uh,
"no" part fits in, my--
What do you mean?
Well, you see, his footsteps,
they sort of led in and out
of the swamp toward
the, uh, outer realms.
It seems that
Faithful is alive.
[GASP]
[HEAVY MUSIC]
Alive?
Oh, dear.
The Master won't
be happy, will he?
When I need to hear the
obvious, I shall let you know.
Oh, right.
Of course.
Mmm.
We cannot afford to
lose any more fools,
certainly not before the war.
But the Master must be told.
Return to the city.
Spread a rumor that
something too horrible
to recount befell Faithful.
The less you say, the
more their imagination
will fill in the blanks.
Ah!
Brilliant.
Yes, a brilliant plan.
Go.
I won't be long.
Right away, my superior.
Right away.
[HEAVY MUSIC]
[EERIE WHOOSHING]
[GENTLE MUSIC]
[GROWL]
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
Master?
What is it?
Master...
I do not need to be
reminded of my position.
Yes, of course.
One of your subjects,
a man called Faithful,
he has gone missing.
Well, he hasn't really
gone missing since we know
he's gone to the outer realms.
I see.
I knew you would be
understanding, Master.
We do try our best to--
[SCREAM]
What gives you the impression
that I am understanding?
I-- I-- I--
I-- I--
Get out!
It won't happen again,
Master, I can assure--
Creature.
Master?
Be vigilant.
One fool has a tendency
to engender another.
[WHOOSHING]
[GENTLE MUSIC]
What am I doing?
All I have is this--this map.
What if I don't get
back to the city in time
to rescue them?
What should I do?
I believe I can
answer that question.
I didn't see you there.
That's because I
just showed up.
My name is Evangelist.
Now, "What should I
do?" you were asking.
And I shall tell you.
Flee.
Flee?
Don't hesitate.
Don't waste time.
Do what you know you must.
You'll soon see
with your eyes
what you believe
in your heart,
and you'll get rid of
that thing on your back.
You can see it?
Well, of course, I can, and
I daresay a heavy and sickly
burden it is.
Oh, it seems to grow
more by the day.
As your sorrows do, dear
lad, so does your burden.
But you'll never get rid of it
on your own, I guarantee you.
Now, do you see that
gate over there?
[LIGHT MUSIC]
Gate?
Where?
Come, come now.
Don't wipe away your tears.
Look through them.
Sometimes tears have a
way of bringing clarity.
I still can't--
Look past your sorrow,
good Christian.
I-- oh.
Wait.
I think I see it.
There, I do.
Near the light.
Good.
Now, listen to me.
Keep that light in your eye,
and go straight towards it.
Do not turn to the
right or to the left.
Keep--
--on the straight path.
Very good.
Now, soon enough, you
will come to the gate.
The gate.
And there, you will
be told what to do.
Now, go.
All right.
Quickly.
Don't waste any more time.
Run.
Run?
But why?
Because the well-intended may
not know what's best at all!
That way!
I think I hear him!
What?
Come on.
Run!
Right behind you!
[TENSE MUSIC]
There!
I think I see him now!
Christian!
For goodness sake.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Get over here.
[BOTH PANTING]
Obstinate?
What are you doing here?
Trying to keep you from making
a greater fool of yourself
than you already have.
Your wife told me
what happened, and--
I need to get to--
No, I will not let go
until you promise
to listen to reason.
I must.
Nope.
Not budging.
All right.
Finally.
[LIGHT PLODDING MUSIC]
Well, Pliable, thanks
for being my backup.
You got him.
Well?
Ready to go back?
No.
All right, then.
Have a good trip.
Get back here.
Sure.
And where are you going?
I said I'd listen.
I didn't say I'd stop.
Oh, bother.
Wait for me, Christian.
And why on Earth would
we leave all we love?
Yeah.
Why?
Because it pales by
comparison to all
that the King of
the Celestial City
promises to his subjects--
fullness of joy in the
presence of the King.
Oh.
No more sorrow.
Whoa.
Streets paved with gold.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
The city I leave behind is
filled with evil and misery.
He's got a point there.
Will you be quiet?
You're really not helping.
All right.
The city I seek is
all goodness and joy
and lasts forever.
I want to find that city
and come back to tell others
how to get there.
You can read about it all
right here in the Book.
See?
No, I don't see.
And quite frankly,
I don't want to.
That Book, which
you should never
have taken in the first
place, has done nothing
but set you on a
journey to a dream.
Speaking of which,
it's getting late,
and I miss my pillow.
So, will you go with me or
not, you stubborn-headed man?
I was going to ask
you the same thing.
Well, I see you, too,
are obstinate, though
for all the wrong reasons.
Come along, Pliable.
Let him go on.
We tried.
Did you not hear me?
Did you not hear him?
Streets of gold.
No more sorrow.
What?
Don't be a fool.
All right.
Well, then?
Endless work.
Things falling apart.
Streets of gold.
No more sorrow.
Hmm.
See ya.
Well.
I find no harm in
changing my mind.
Obviously.
Are you sure you won't
change yours, Obstinate?
Do I look like I want to?
You fools, walking
to your death.
Oh.
Your poor wife and
the Supervisors
shall have my full report.
So streets of gold,
no more sorrow.
Tell on.
What else?
Life unending.
Peace of heart.
Joy forever in the
presence of the King.
Shining garments.
Oh, what bliss.
What are we waiting for?
Let's get there as
soon as possible!
[BOTH SHOUT]
[HEAVY MUSIC]
What is this?
Oh.
Mud?
Pliable?
Are you all--
take my--
I knew I shouldn't
have listened to you.
Here.
Streets of gold.
Shining garments.
If this is what it's like to
follow you in the beginning,
how could it possibly be
any better in the end?
So much for your Book.
I have no problem
changing my mind.
No, sir.
Please!
Help me!
[TENSE MUSIC]
[TWINKLING MUSIC]
You called?
Huh?
I called for help.
I didn't know what else to do.
And I have come,
for that is my name.
Oh.
Thank you.
Better?
Why didn't you use the steps?
Steps?
[GENTLE MUSIC]
Covered again.
The King placed them there
to help people like you.
But no sooner is
the swamp drained
that it fills to overflowing
again with the fears, doubts,
and discouragement of those
that make it this far.
So this is--
Yes.
Looks like mud.
Sticks like mud.
And it'll keep a
person down like mud.
But it isn't.
It's a mess of fears,
the Swamp of Despondency.
The place where people
like your friend
there give up before
they even start.
But it was right, you know.
Right?
To go back, I mean.
But--
This journey you're embarking
on, not for the double-minded.
No, no.
Not for the wishy-washy.
Not at all.
And this swamp, it's
nothing compared
to the trouble that's ahead.
Let me ask you a question.
Do you know
the Celestial King?
He sent me here.
Have you seen the
Celestial City?
I surely have.
Then step aside.
I know the way will be rough.
I've read about
that in the Book.
I can only hope
for the King's help
as I continue on
my journey, which
I am determined to complete.
And I need no
convincing, Christian,
for I have no
doubts that you have
turned your face to the light
and are not looking back.
Continue your trek.
And do not forget.
Help, in some form or
another, is never far away.
Thank you, again, for--
[GRUNTS]
It's mud.
You still had a little
bit of mud on you.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Farewell!
Remember-- help, in some form
or another, is never far away.
[HEAVY MUSIC]
Oh, dear.
Another man has gone...
Oh.
You've heard already.
Yes, I did.
And so has the
Master, obviously.
He has gone beyond the
swamp into the outer realms.
So there's nothing we can do.
Oh, but there is.
In the outer realms,
we cannot impede him.
But we can dissuade him with
fear, with doubt, with pride.
There are many,
many persuasions.
[LAUGHS]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[SOFT MUSIC]
What I wouldn't do to
get rid of this thing.
I'd give anything
in the world to--
[LIGHT TWINKLING MUSIC]
Whatever is the
matter, dear boy?
And what in the world is that
awful thing on your back?
I'm actually on my way to--
Where are my manners?
Worldly's the name.
Worldly first, Wiseman
last, of course.
Don't ever mix them up.
You were saying?
That I am on my way
to the Celestial City
by way of the gate,
where I hope to get
rid of this burden which is
getting bigger by the hour.
Oh, and you would do well
to do that, dear boy.
But--
Yes?
Well, who told you you could
get rid of that over there?
A good man that came upon me
in my hour of need, Evang--
--gelist, of course.
Oh, dear, dear, dear.
[TSKS]
What is it?
And you've already
come all this way.
Oh, dear, dear, dear.
Well, what?
It's just that
this Evangelist--
Yes?
Well, he's a little--
[COOING]
So he's--
Yes, he is.
Loony as a bird.
The poor chap has his
head in the clouds.
Oh, no.
So what on Earth was
this Evangelist thinking,
sending you in that direction?
Full of nothing but
trouble and danger,
which I can see
by the scratches
and the tears and the mud,
you've already experienced.
So don't go that direction,
which is silly nonsense.
But you go in this
direction, which is not.
But--
No "but."
Do not argue with me.
You listen.
So you keep going that way.
[LIGHT PLODDING MUSIC]
Good boy.
You keep going that
way, and do not stop.
No matter what things
begin to look like, just
go in the direction I
tell you until you get
to a village called Morality.
There, you will find the Hill.
You will know you're at the
Hill because the signs will
tell you.
There, not at that silly gate
you were telling me about,
you will be told how to
get rid of that ugly thing.
[HEAVY MUSIC]
Who goes there?
I say, who goes there?
My name is Christian.
I was told to ask
for a gentleman
by the name of Legality.
A man, I am, of sorts.
But gentle, I am not.
[LAUGHS]
I was told that you
could get rid of this--
Stop your blubbering,
and get on with it.
I've haven't got all day.
That you could get rid
of this burden for me.
Indeed, I can.
Oh.
Well, then, please.
Will you?
Well, I can't very well
come down to you now, can I?
I am a mountain!
You will have to come to me.
But how?
Follow the instructions.
Which ones?
All of them, of course.
[LAUGHS]
But there are too many.
Too many?
Why, can there ever be enough?
[CHRISTIAN WHIMPERS]
Come now.
You want that burden
off, don't you?
Come to me.
But--
Do as I say.
Come, now.
You're still too far away.
I can hardly see you now.
Keep up, man.
Keep up.
I can't do the work for you.
You missed a sign there.
You missed one, I say.
I can't.
[CHRISTIAN SCREAMS]
You expect me to help you when
you cannot even help yourself?
On your feet.
Oh.
What am I going to do?
[FOOTSTEPS]
[GASP]
Uh-oh.
How is it you've turned
out of the way so quickly?
I don't know.
Ha!
Oh, dear.
Ow!
Come on.
Let's get you out
from under all that.
Commandments cannot give
you what you seek, Christian.
They will only be a
reminder that you are not
able to keep them all.
Legality can never rid you
of your burden, you know.
Say what?
I said--
I'll show you what I can do.
Prepare to see my
power, you wretched man.
Christian!
Run!
Bury you are under the
weight of my power,
I will, and rid the world
of your burden and you.
[LEGALITY GRUNTS]
[CHRISTIAN SHOUTS]
[LEGALITY LAUGHS]
[TENSE HEAVY MUSIC]
[COUGHING]
Here we are.
When Legality comes
toppling down,
we are catapulted
to the way, the way
that you left off following.
It wasn't really my fault.
Oh, I see.
A man I met, a Mr. Worldly--
Ah.
That scoundrel.
Well, he said there
was an easier way
to get rid of my burden.
And I-- well, I--
Was led out of this way.
I thought--
You thought the King was
leading you down a wrong path.
Well, no.
I--
You brought this
misery upon yourself
by rejecting the very
instructions the King sent
to you, Christian.
You're right.
It is my fault.
I had no business
listening to Worldly Wiseman.
It's no one's fault but mine.
And I'm sorry.
I'm--
Forgiven.
What?
I'm--
Forgiven.
If tears are any indication
of regret, yours are.
The King has said every
misstep will be forgiven.
Now, stand up.
Continue the journey, for
you have no time to lose.
But learn, Christian,
that there are two things
this deceiver
caused you to do.
The first is that he caused
you to so easily go out
of the way and,
second, that he made
the difficulty of your journey
something you wanted to avoid.
Now, off to the gate with you.
And remember, good Christian,
do not leave the path again.
[LIGHT MUSIC]
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
You failed miserably.
But I got him to
go out of the way.
And then you left him.
In the hands of Worldly
Wiseman and Legality.
I was certain he would
be caught in their maze.
He was ours.
And now he is not.
[RUMBLING]
[SHOUT]
[GROWLING]
What would you have me do?
Get the others.
Send out the legion.
Do what you must.
Yes, Master.
Yes.
Do not let him near that gate.
Stop him.
Stop him!
[INTENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[SOFT FOREBODING MUSIC]
[RUSTLING]
[SOFT GROWL]
[PANTING]
Oh.
Calm down.
[INTENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[SCREAM]
[GROWL]
[CREATURES GROWLING]
[SCREAM]
The gate.
[LAUGHS] At last.
[LIGHT MUSIC]
[HEAVY DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[CREATURES SCREECHING]
Help will come in
some form or another.
Help will-- help!
Help!
[ETHEREAL MUSIC]
Knock, and it will be--
[CREATURES GROWLING]
Open the door!
Yes?
My name is Christian, and I--
Let me in!
Ah.
The very words.
I made it.
For a moment, I thought
I wouldn't, but I did.
Ha! I did.
No one gets turned away here.
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
What are you doing?
Well, I was told this would
come off once I got here.
I believe the words
were, "And there, you
will be told what to do."
Oh.
Very well, then.
I'd say you'd better run.
Run?
And by the looks of it,
the sooner, the better.
Come on.
But I thought my
journey was over.
Over?
Oh, no, dear boy.
Your journey's just beginning.
And if I were you, I'd--
[GROWLING]
--make a dash for it now.
But--
Go, quickly!
But how will I know
which way to go?
The straight path.
Always the straight.
It will lead you
to the Interpreter.
Now, go.
[INTENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[MAN SHOUTS]
Come and get it,
you winged rats!
Slime bags!
Take that!
[CREATURES SCREECHING]
[MAN GRUNTING]
[POWERFUL DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[SOFT MUSIC]
Ow!
I could sure use
some help about now.
[TWINKLING MUSIC]
[LAUGH]
What is this?
You want me to follow you?
[LAUGH]
[CHRISTIAN LAUGHING]
[GRUNT]
[LIGHT GENTLE MUSIC]
[DOOR CREAKS OPEN]
Who are you?
My dear, dear boy.
Why, I am the Interpreter.
I've been expecting you.
And I was expecting
a house of some sort.
Things are not always what
they seem, dear Christian.
And sometimes, life's
tumbles can lead you
to the most
interesting of places.
The Gatekeeper was right to
say you would be helped here.
Is there something the matter?
The light, it seems
to follow you.
[LAUGHS] As it should.
I am the Interpreter.
I bring light where
there are shadows.
I see.
Do you really, Christian?
Do I really--
See and understand?
Well, now I'm
beginning not to.
On your way here, you
walked in darkness.
I am here, Christian,
to give light
to the rest of your journey.
[ETHEREAL MUSIC]
Who are they?
We are the followers
of the King who
leads us by way of
the light in His book.
The King's promises
are ever at their side,
and their gaze is to the
things which last forever.
Keep this in mind,
Christian, for you
will meet people
who will pretend
to lead you in the right and
will only lead you into--
[BABY CRYING]
--misery.
And this?
This is--
Passion, who throws a
horrid tantrum because he
wants things.
No!
[INTERPRETER TSKS]
Won't you be a dear
when you grow up?
Patience, on the other hand,
[LAUGH]
is happy to enjoy
things as they come.
You are learning to look
and not just see, Christian.
Very good.
And the interpretation
here is that...
I must be content to wait
in patience for the things
the King has promised me and
not be tempted out of the way.
The things you have seen will
help you on your journey.
And, lastly--
No!
[SOMBER MUSIC]
If you are wondering why he
remains in the cage, ask him.
Sir, why are you
in such despair?
No hope.
I beg your pardon?
Sir, I cannot hear you.
No hope.
No hope!
That last one, it was
very unpleasant.
As despair can tend to be.
But what did it mean?
That is for you to interpret
when the time comes.
My gift to help
you on your way may
be summed up in these words.
Look.
Do not just see.
Listen.
And--
And do not just hear.
You are ready to
continue your journey.
Ponder the things you
have learned today,
that they may prod
your sides and lead you
to that place your
heart so longs for.
[MUSIC - "BE THOU MY VISION"]
(SINGING) Be Thou my
vision, O Lord of my heart.
Naught be all else to
me, save that Thou art.
Thou my best thought
by day or by night.
Waking or sleeping,
Thy presence my light.
Patience Path.
Passion Passage.
Which one?
Look.
Do not just--
See.
[SIGH] This doesn't
make sense to me.
But I have not gone
wrong to follow
the King's Road, no matter
how difficult it may seem.
(SINGING) Riches I heed
not, nor man's empty praise.
Thou mine inheritance
now and always.
Thou and Thou only,
first in my heart.
High King of heaven,
my treasure Thou art.
If I am to go forward, the
King shall give me strength.
And if He wills
to ease my load--
[LIGHT POWERFUL MUSIC]
What?
[WHOOSHING]
Oh.
Joy!
What am I nearing
that my burden is
finally being loosed?
[LAUGHS]
Oh, I was right to
follow the King's path,
for with each step,
He is setting me free!
(SINGING) High King of
heaven, my victory won.
May I reach heaven's joys,
O bright heaven's sun.
Heart of my own heart,
whatever befall,
still be my vision,
O Ruler of all.
I'm free!
[GLASS SHATTERING]
Do you understand what
just happened, Christian?
Who are you?
We are the King's heralds.
Do you understand
what just happened?
My heart, it has
been cleansed.
My King did for me what I
and no one else could do.
He has rid me of my burden.
And He has given me new life.
Indeed, He has.
New garments for a new life.
The King has made
you one of His own.
You walk as a prince
before Him, Christian.
My heart is overwhelmed with
thanks, for my filthy rags
and the heavy burden
have been taken from me.
And in their place, such
blessing, such great blessing
beyond compare.
For now, continue
on your journey
until you reach the
Palace Beautiful.
There, you will be refreshed
and readied for
what lies ahead.
[MASTER GROWLS]
[SUPERVISOR GROANS]
[HEAVY OMINOUS MUSIC]
There was nothing we could do.
We tried.
But not well enough.
We--we have failed you.
[MASTER GROWLS]
Perhaps--perhaps he
will simply be forgotten.
Perhaps we should
just let him be.
Let him be?
Let him be?!
The fool is a greater threat
to us now than he was before.
Threat?
But how?
He will not be forgotten.
Others will try
the same thing.
No.
He must be stopped.
But, sire, he bears the seal.
Do you think me that helpless?
Have you not seen
how many I have
caused to turn away even
this far into their journey?
By the time I am through
with this-- this Christian,
he shall be lying in a
pool of his own blood.
[FOREBODING MUSIC]
At last.
[GROWLING]
What was that?
What-- what is that?
Just forest animals.
[INTENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[GROWLING]
What should I do?
I must go forward.
Help.
Help...
Come.
Come, good Christian.
[CHRISTIAN SHOUTS]
Come.
Now, now, good Christian.
You've shown great courage.
You have passed a
trial of your faith.
Barely.
But, well, my
name is Watchful,
and this is my
home, and yours.
My heart is still pounding.
I fear I have almost
lost my newfound joy.
Well, you'd have to be
dead not to feel some fear.
Do not let that perturb you.
Now you are here with
me and my daughters,
Discretion, Prudence,
Piety, and sweet Charity.
We welcome you to our
family, good Christian.
Thank you.
Thank you for
your hospitality.
I've never seen
anything like this.
The King of the Celestial
City built this house
for the purpose of refreshing
pilgrims such as yourself.
It is now your house
as well as ours.
Others have taken the same
path you now journey on.
Let their example be an
encouragement to you,
for you are now part of
their glorious company.
You no longer walk alone.
Now, please.
Come to the table.
[GENTLE MUSIC]
And that's what set
me on this path.
But I must say that every step
has taught me something new,
and every hardship
strengthened me.
I have learned that the
King wastes nothing.
And, well, here I am,
still in one piece.
[LAUGHTER]
And your family?
[SIGH]
Sister.
I only ask because I
see them in your heart.
It is my one regret.
I wish I had been better
at convincing them.
There is no need to hide your
tears here, dear Christian.
You are among family.
I love my wife, and I
love my children dearly.
It does me good
to speak of them
since I carry them
in my heart,
holding on to
the King's promise
that they, too, may
understand and follow
or that I might have peace
if they choose not to.
Be assured.
The King is aware
of your sorrow.
And not one tear shed
for them is lost.
Be at peace, good Christian,
and lay your burdens
at the feet of your King,
for not one hair of your head
falls without Him knowing.
Now, come.
There is a special
place for you tonight
to rest your weary head,
your heart, and your soul.
I think it suits him.
Of course.
He's fitted for a purpose.
It's not as comfortable
as my other clothes.
But more in keeping with the
next stage of your journey.
Now, let's accompany him to--
Oh, no need to
bother yourself-- oh!
Oh, dear.
Oh, my.
I'm fine.
I guess it's just as
dangerous going down
a hill than climbing up.
[SHOUT]
It is difficult for
anyone to go down
to the Valley of Humiliation.
And when they do,
they must walk alone.
The what?
It sounded like you
said the Valley of--
[GASPS]
[FOREBODING MUSIC]
What is this?
Where am I?
So, a sword, a shield, armor.
They were preparing
me for battle.
[HEAVY MUSIC]
Courage.
Courage!
Why, Christian.
What are you doing here
in this horrid place
so far away from
your comfortable home
and loving family?
Who are you?
You don't recognize me?
[LAUGHS] Why, I
am your prince.
My prince?
Now, really.
A sword.
As you can see, I am unarmed.
Now, let's go back.
Back?
Christiana and the boys.
You have no idea how
much they miss you.
Father, come home.
Come home.
If you'd only return.
You miss them, don't you?
I do.
Father, where are you?
Come home.
Oh, Christian, why?
But I am on this
journey for the King,
and I will not be dissuaded.
So noble.
Believe me, no one
admires you more
than I. But think about it.
Even if you reach
your destination, what
will become of those you love?
Perhaps you'll save yourself.
But what of them?
No.
I think it's best
you return with me.
Now...
[EERIE MUSIC]
Put down your sword.
[TENSE MUSIC]
And their gaze is to the
things which last forever.
Keep this in mind,
Christian, for you
will meet people
who will pretend
to lead you in the right and
will only lead you into--
Misery.
What?
The King has never failed me.
And I will not fail
Him, you deceiver,
you liar, you usurper
of all that is good--
Silence.
--and true.
I served under you and
found nothing but misery.
Silence!
My allegiance is with
the Celestial King.
Is it?
You heard me.
How many times
have you already failed
Him on this journey?
You are a disgrace to
this King of yours.
Which makes His mercy and
forgiveness the sweeter.
You are a deceiver that
binds your subjects
with invisible chains.
The King has broken
mine, and I am free.
I follow Him.
Then prepare to
forfeit your journey,
for I swear you
will go no further.
[TENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[CHRISTIAN SHOUTS]
[MASTER GROWLS]
[GROWLING]
[CHRISTIAN SHOUTS]
[OMINOUS ETHEREAL MUSIC]
You're mine!
Do not gloat over
me, you fiend.
Though I have fallen,
I will yet arise!
[INTENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
You will see me
again, Christian,
when the waves overpower
you, when death's cold arms
wrap themselves around
your wretched soul,
I will be there!
[SCREAMS] Be gone!
Be-- be gone.
[SOFT MUSIC]
[GASP]
Faithful?
And you are?
And so you found the Book.
By them, I learned
about the coming war,
the origins of our city.
A cursed city, a city so
opposite in nature to the one
you and I journey to.
One that will last--
Forever.
Evangelist.
[LAUGHTER]
It's good to see
you, Christian.
This is the man who
showed me the way.
And a treasure he is to
me as well, for I also
am indebted to him.
But tell us.
What brings you this way?
The joy of your company.
Now, how about some food?
Ha.
A double blessing.
Oh, and it could not have
come at a better time.
[EVANGELIST LAUGHS]
Come then, friends,
and rest awhile.
I am glad
not that you have had to
face so many challenges,
but that you faced
them with such faith
and continued in the way.
A crown, dear Christian and
Faithful, awaits you both,
and it will last forever.
But be advised, my friends,
that you are not yet
out of the reach of evil.
And--
And?
[SOMBER MUSIC]
What more do you
have to tell us?
You--
You didn't just come
here to sip tea.
There's more, is there not?
You cannot expect to
continue without hardships.
But we've already proven
ourselves capable of that.
And we have the
dents to prove it.
[CHRISTIAN LAUGHS]
No.
I mean severe, more
difficult hardships,
hardships from which
you might not escape.
Meaning?
You will soon come to a town
where you will be arrested.
Arrested?
And one or both of you
will seal your
testimony with blood.
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
The town you will go
through is unique.
Welcome to Vanity Fair.
It was constructed by the evil
Apollyon on the very path that
leads to the Celestial City.
A pie, I say.
The town hosts a
fair that never ends.
[LIGHT PLAYFUL MUSIC]
[CHATTER]
And in it, you will
encounter everything
that tempts a human heart.
Look, Fortunata.
I've never laid eyes
on these before.
Through this town,
you must go.
Come now, strangers!
Try our spirits!
But be warned.
Do not be overly confident,
and heed to this warning.
Settle it in your
heart what you will
do before you enter
the town, for many
have fallen who walked in
with one eye on eternity
and the other on the present.
I would keep my
eye on those two.
--and, well, just about
anything you like.
Or the vests.
Have you seen the vests?
You can't be here
without playing a game.
No!
[GASP]
No?
What we wish to obtain,
you do not sell here.
That, sir, is impossible.
Did you hear what he said?
What is going on here?
What is the meaning
of this disruption?
These strange strangers
insist that what they need
is not available here.
And as a result, they
have disrupted our fair.
Well, then, to the Judge.
Out of my way.
What?
But we have done nothing.
Excuse me.
Make way.
Yes.
Make way, I say.
[LIGHT PLAYFUL MUSIC]
This is preposterous.
Put the scoundrels away.
What is the meaning of this?
What is this
interruption to our fair?
What?
These strange strangers.
What did they do?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Exactly.
They won't take
part in anything.
They won't buy anything.
They are doing nothing.
Well, by doing nothing, you
have interrupted our fair.
There's only one thing to do.
Call the jury.
Jury!
[WHIRRING]
[BELL DINGS]
All present.
Right.
Do we have the witnesses?
Envy and Gain Glory.
Do you know these prisoners?
Yes, at least 15 minutes.
And what do you
hold against them?
They said that what they
wanted we did not have.
And what could
that possibly be?
Peace, joy,
love, unselfishness,
patience, contentment.
And a crown that never fades
away, among other things.
Do we sell that?
[ALL CHATTERING]
Quiet in the court.
Quiet in the court!
Come, come.
Do we sell any
of these things?
Of course not.
This is Vanity Fair,
not La La Land.
I wouldn't even know where
to get those kinds of things.
Well, I have been informed
that such things as you speak
of cannot be sold, else
you would find it aplenty
in our fabulous fair.
And that you say truthfully,
for they can only
be obtained by the
King who gives them
to all who desire them.
Though they come not at
the price of any coin,
but of the surrender of the
heart to His better ways.
[COUGHS]
You have proof that these
wonderful things even exist?
By the King's grace.
Well, then, show them to us.
They are not such things as
you can hold in your hand.
But are most excellent things
which are held in the heart
and are the most valuable
during hardships,
for it is then that their
worth is most evident.
Well, then, may I suggest
just that, my lord,
that we may see what we
are so missing out on?
Suggest what?
Why, hardships, of course.
Hardships?
Hardships.
Cruelty, approach the bench.
What are you thinking?
The fair has been disrupted.
Is that not cause enough?
I am ready for judgment.
But not the townspeople.
What are you talking about?
Did you not see
how they reacted to the
comments of these two men?
I say punish them
harshly and openly
that our people have evidence
that these two fools possess
nothing of this-- this
peace, love, unselfishness,
and blah-blah that
they so boast about.
And therefore, that
our townspeople
are not missing out
on anything at all.
Oh, I see.
I do, indeed.
Very well, then.
I will postpone my
judgment until evidence
has been submitted.
Commence the hardship,
and resume the fair.
What are you doing?
Unhand me.
Well, that's over.
Let's get back to some fun.
[LIGHT PLAYFUL MUSIC]
And away we go.
[LAUGHTER, CHATTER]
So you got something
better than us.
Right in the head.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
This is better than the fair.
Need more rocks.
[LAUGHS] Look at them now.
They what?
Took every blow, every
rock, every insult.
And not once did
they retaliate?
They even tried to smile
back at their attackers.
No.
How vile!
How very unnatural of them.
How purely evil.
I say the sooner we get
rid of them, the better.
It's unanimous.
Bring in the prisoners.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
The evidence was not
to our satisfaction.
Our behavior was in
keeping with our--
Order!
[HEAVY OMINOUS MUSIC]
I sentence you to death.
What?
Starting with him.
You can't.
Well, I just did.
No!
All right, everyone.
Back to the fair.
Faithful.
Faithful!
Do not worry, my dear brother.
This is what Evangelist
came to prepare us for.
Today, I seal my
testimony with my blood.
Faithful.
No!
Do not weep that I am sent
ahead of you, dear brother.
Stay true, and I
shall yet see you.
No!
I shall yet see you!
Don't worry.
You'll have your
turn tomorrow.
Put him away.
Faithful.
Faithful!
[HEAVY SOMBER MUSIC]
[PEOPLE SHOUTING]
Oh, Faithful.
My dear brother, Faithful.
Give me strength, and help me.
Help me, please.
Please.
Drat.
The fair is
resuming, and here we
are guarding this one
who's as good as dead.
You took the words
right out of my mouth.
And I've got an idea.
You go along and
enjoy the fair.
I'll stay guard.
No use both of us missing out.
You come back later,
and we'll switch.
I don't know.
Look.
No one will know.
You say nothing, and--
Say no more.
Whoopee!
I'll see you soon!
[TENSE MUSIC]
Huh?
[FOREBODING MUSIC]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[TENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Ah!
No!
Please!
You're one of the
guards from that city,
and I am not going back.
Neither am I. I'm not
here to apprehend you.
I'm here to go with you.
When I heard what
your companion--
Faithful.
Yes, when I heard what
Faithful had to say,
it made sense to me.
I'm not the only one in Vanity
Fair that feels this way.
There are others.
Perhaps that's the reason the
path leads through the city.
So other sojourners can
help people like you.
You see that I've
left everything.
I cannot go back.
And so you shall go with me.
But I just realized,
I do not yet know your name.
Hopeful.
Then, rest tonight, as your
name implies, brave Hopeful.
For tomorrow, we
journey on to our King.
[GENTLE MUSIC]
My dear brother, Faithful,
you did not die in vain.
The path is a
little rocky here.
But look!
What impedes us from walking
that side of the path?
But what if it leads
us out of the way?
How can it?
It runs parallel.
Look-- side by side
as far as you can see.
I am sure if we
cut across there,
we can then climb
back over the wall
and avoid that entire trek.
Follow me.
[HOPEFUL LAUGHS]
[CHRISTIAN LAUGHS]
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
I can't even see
the path anymore.
We'll have to turn
back the way we came.
I never thought--
[THUNDER]
Oh, no.
[HEAVY MUSIC]
I don't know, Hopeful.
I really think we
need to head back.
But we can't even see
which way to go now.
Look.
Let's shelter there
for a while.
We can wait it out here.
It should be over soon.
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
[BOTH SHOUT]
And what do we have here?
[TENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
(WHISPERING) You're never
getting out of here.
[VOICES WHISPERING]
(WHISPERING) How
many are your errors?
How wrong you have
been. How stupid.
How long has it been?
Six days.
No food.
No water.
This is all my fault.
We've discussed this
so many times already.
But it was my idea.
And I agreed to it.
You must really try and
get that out of your mind.
(WHISPERING) Just one slash.
[VOICES WHISPERING]
(WHISPERING) You're doomed.
We're doomed, you and I.
What?
(WHISPERING) Doomed.
Have you seen the
bones down there?
I honestly don't want to.
We're dead.
Let's just hope he
doesn't come down again.
Oh.
No.
(WHISPERING) Just die.
[VOICES WHISPERING]
I don't think I can
take this much longer.
What?
Are you still alive?
I gave you everything you
needed to do the job--
knives, clubs, rope.
What more could I do?
Why didn't you
do yourselves in?
And now you've
got me very up--
[GROANS]
[SNORING]
What happened?
Did he just faint?
Not again.
Oh, dear.
I should've listened
to me mum when
she warned me to marry you.
Could've have me pick
of any eligible giant
being the beauty I was.
But no.
I had to pick the
pretty one, I did.
Now look at you, fainting like
an old woman any time you get
the slightest bit worked up.
Why, I oughta--
[SCREAMS]
[HOPEFUL AND CHRISTIAN SHOUT]
[FEMALE GIANT GRUNTING]
[INTENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
All right.
Why didn't she just kill
us, just get it over with?
(WHISPERING) How
many are your errors?
How stupid.
Because she can't.
What?
Did you see her hands?
She could crush us
with her little finger.
That's just it.
She-- they can,
but they can't.
Why didn't I see it before?
I really have no
idea what you mean.
Look, up there
near the ceiling.
What do you see?
Skulls.
A big skull, a bigger skull--
No, in the middle,
the coat of arms.
It's the name of this
realm, this castle.
Desperatio.
The Castle of Despair.
That's why they want
us to kill ourselves.
That's why we can't get out.
Wait.
I don't think I understand.
What did the giant say?
"I gave you everything
to do the job."
Don't you see?
They can't kill.
They can only make the
situation so miserable
that you do it yourself.
There's always been a way of
escape for you, hasn't there?
That's got to be some way out.
There's got to be.
No hope.
No hope!
That was me.
That was me in the cage.
Now I'm the one in the dark.
What is the opposite
of despair?
I don't know.
Hope.
[THRUMMING]
What is that?
[LIGHT TINKLING MUSIC]
[GASPS] The way out.
[POWERFUL DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Shh.
Quiet now.
Just a little more, and--
[DOOR CREAKING]
[BOTH LAUGH]
We did it.
Hopeful.
[CREAKING]
Hopeful!
[TENSE MUSIC]
[FOREBODING MUSIC]
What was that?
[GASP]
Oh, you good-for-nothing.
Be calm.
Don't get him worked up.
Poochie-poo.
Oh, whisker-pants.
Huh?
The prisoners,
they're escaping.
[TENSE DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[SHOUT]
Quickly.
You get them, cherry lips!
Or I'll wring your neck.
Get back here!
[HOPEFUL AND CHRISTIAN SHOUT]
That's good, dear.
You're doing very well.
Really, very well, you
good-for-nothing oaf.
Oh, dear.
[GIANT PANTING]
Quickly.
Get them, you blithering fool!
[PLODDING MUSIC]
[GROAN]
[HOPEFUL SCREAMS]
This way.
I should've listened
to me mum.
I should.
But no.
Could've had me pick
of any eligible giant.
But no.
I had to pick the
pretty one, I did.
Pretty stupid.
Pretty smelly.
Now I got to go
down in me nightie
to pick you up off the
ground, you good-for-nothing.
[SOFT MUSIC]
Can you imagine the
trouble that giant
will face from his irate wife?
He'll despair,
that's for certain.
[BOTH LAUGH]
What happened?
I have no idea.
The path seems to
have vanished.
And yet you will
still be guided.
Welcome to the King's
Delightful Mountains,
a taste of things to come.
[SHEEP BLEATS]
Thank you, kind Shepherd.
My name is--
Christian.
And you are Hopeful.
You are known and loved.
Tell me.
Do we know you?
In part.
You will be delighted to hear
that you are within sight
of that city which you
have so diligently sought
and for which you
have also suffered.
That is, indeed, good news.
And the rest of the way,
is it very dangerous?
Let this knowledge
suffice for now--
that you do not walk
alone, for the King guides
you as a shepherd
does his sheep.
He always goes before, even
if out of sight of the sheep.
I give you a map for the
rest of your journey.
Beware the Flatterer.
Do not sleep on the
enchanted ground.
Keep the light of the
city ever before you.
We shall do as you
say, kind Shepherd.
Now, if you please, is
this the way that leads--
where did He go?
He spoke about a map.
Did you give it to you?
I was going to ask
you the same thing.
Alas, it could have come
in handy just about now.
I don't know what
direction to take.
Well, isn't this a sight?
I daresay it's not
every day that one finds
other pilgrims this far along.
I-- well, I'm just beside
myself with joy to meet you.
I'm Christian, and this is
my good friend, Hopeful.
Such names.
They can only reflect your
goodly character, I'm sure.
You're going to the
Celestial City, I suppose?
Indeed, we are.
Then we shall walk together.
But the light of the city
seems to be coming
from over there.
Or so it seems.
Come, come now.
I know exactly
what I am doing.
I am a great judge of
character, you know.
I only accept the company of
those with the same dedicated
inclinations as I.
Well, we have tried to
be faithful, though we
have had our stumblings.
Christian, however, exceeds
me in both virtue and courage,
having begun his journey much
earlier than I. I admire him
completely.
And upon hearing
that, so do I.
Oh, come now.
I'm hardly a model of virtue.
Tut, tut.
You are too modest.
Share with me even a snippet
of one of your
brave adventures,
and I shall be
forever in your debt.
Well, I don't know.
There are so many.
Ah, such humility.
He survived the
Swamp of Despondency.
That despicable mire.
And the Valley of Humiliation.
In which so many
have gone mad.
We escaped the
Castle of Despair.
Which so few seem
to have done,
judging by the bones
scattered there,
I might add.
I should fall at your feet.
Oh, and I fought
Apollyon, you know.
[GASPS] Well, aren't
you the greatest--
[HOPEFUL AND CHRISTIAN SHOUT]
[MAN LAUGHS]
The greatest fool,
I should say!
You.
Surprised?
Do you think we
give up that easily?
Get us out of here.
See these strands?
They were woven by
your own boasting.
And judging by them, I fear
your own pride has kept you
from your destination.
Let us go.
[TSKS]
A pity you will not be able
to get word to your wife
or, shall I say, widow.
[LAUGHS]
[HEAVY MUSIC]
No!
A Flatterer.
What?
He was a Flatterer.
We stepped right
into his trap.
When am I ever going to learn?
Let's not despair
again, Christian.
But now I won't be able--
Stop, please.
Let's not give up hope.
We've got to think back
on what the Shepherd said.
"Beware of the Flatterer."
Before that.
"You do not walk alone."
[SOFT ETHEREAL MUSIC]
And you are not alone now.
[BOTH GRUNT]
That was painful.
Sometimes, Hopeful, a
rescue means wounds.
Did you not meet the Shepherd
of the Delightful Mountains?
We did.
And did He not give you a map?
He only counseled--
And warned us.
But the map, He
didn't give us.
The King's instructions
are a map, Christian.
Did they not indicate where
to go and where not to go?
They did.
I can see that now.
Be vigilant to your
last breath, for you are
very near your journey's end.
How will we know
when we are there?
When you stand at the
brink of the last shadow,
the border beyond which
evil has no power, where
the old is left forever
and newness of life begins.
Do not fear to cross, for
your eternal city lies beyond.
You will find your step
deeper or shallower
as you believe in the
superiority of the King.
Where are you going?
Can you not see
the city beyond?
I'm looking for the crossing.
Christian.
I don't understand.
There doesn't seem to be
any way to get across.
No way around it.
No way over it.
Only through it.
What are you talking about?
There's no way--
Can't you see what this is?
This is the last shadow,
the borders beyond which
evil has no power--
Death.
Death?
Where the old is left forever
and newness of life begins.
We can go forward.
But we can never go back.
[SOFT HEAVY MUSIC]
I'm going.
Hopeful?
I am going, Christian.
And I-- I'm not.
You have to.
You've come this far.
To make a way for
others, Hopeful.
To make a way from
my wife, my family--
to save them.
And that, you cannot do, for
the way has already been paved
for others by the same
one that paved it for you.
Your part has been to follow.
And, believe me, it has
caused no lack of talk
among the people of
your former city.
Others will follow.
Including my wife
and children?
That question, dear Christian,
can only be answered by them.
But if they do, would you
lead them to this point only
or to a new and
everlasting life
in which evil has no part?
I'm going.
I must.
Hopeful.
All through our
journey, you told me
that the King's ways
never failed you,
that His promises were true.
I know He will
not fail me now.
Goodbye, dear brother.
Hopeful!
He's gone.
To the Celestial
City, to all that
has been promised, to what
you both sought so diligently.
Well?
I'm afraid.
And there is nothing
wrong with that.
You have trusted the King
with your life, Christian.
And I, dear friend,
I shall trust him with my--
[POWERFUL DRAMATIC MUSIC]
You will see me
again, Christian,
when the waves overpower you,
when death's cold arms wrap
themselves around
your wretched soul.
I will be there.
No!
You will find your step
deeper or shallower
as you believe in the
superiority of the King.
Help!
[HEAVY DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[GROWL]
[SCREAM]
I'm bleeding.
[ETHEREAL MUSIC]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[GASP]
You.
[GENTLE MUSIC]
You're the Shepherd.
I am.
I am the Good Shepherd.
I saw the blood.
I was bleeding.
It was not your blood,
Christian, but mine.
And you needn't worry
any longer about wounds,
for you have arrived
to the place where
the old is passed away and
newness of life begins.
Welcome, Christian.
Welcome to the Celestial City.
[BRIGHT POWERFUL MUSIC]
Haha!
Welcome, brother!
Christian!
Welcome!
Christian, my dear brother.
Hopeful?
Faithful!
[LAUGHS] My friends!
My brothers.
Oh, that my dear
ones could see this,
that they, too, would come...
that they, too, would come!
[LIGHT MUSIC]
[MUSIC - "BLESSED ASSURANCE"]
(SINGING) This is my story.
This is my song.
Praising my Savior
all the day long.
This is my story.
This is my song.
Praising my Savior
all the day long.
[GENTLE MUSIC]
I know this will break your
heart, as it does mine.
But I am going
because I have no doubt
the Book speaks truth.
I have taken a promise
from its pages, which
I will carry near my heart.
"Eye has not seen.
Ear has not heard.
Neither can anyone imagine
the wonderful things
the King has prepared
for those that seek Him."
Christian is alive!
[POWERFUL MUSIC]
Boys?
Boys, wake up.
Your father's alive.
Your father is alive!
[CREATURE SCREECHES]