[Music]
oh
i thought this was supposed to be a
modern school everyone was tolerant and
respectful of other people's rights
if i haven't even got a right to my own
[Music]
name
i'm ashamed of you
let me scrub one more thing i hate about
this school
being called by your surname but what's
matter
them again i wish my parents had never
sent me to this place
it's horrible now look here i'll go away
and mind your own business
i should have known you'd be on their
side is that fair
i may have been like that last year you
were horrible
but yes you have changed everyone's
noticed it
but that lot have got you marked down as
their next victim
we can hide better there
[Music]
now
why are you so changed it was during the
holidays
a lot of weird things happen to me what
kind of things
i think i can trust you but it's the
most terrific secret
do you believe right outside this world
our world i don't even know what that
means
in a place where animals can talk
and there are dragons and enchantments
how did you get there the only way
anyone can
buy magic i think i'm getting a bit old
for match
i'll come off it
but i i know what you mean he's with my
cousins
and they can't go back because they're
too old
i certainly wish we could get away from
here
he never said i couldn't go back
i'm sure if i really wanted to he'd let
me who
eustis what are you talking about a
certain someone
how you mean draw a magic circle on the
ground and stand in it no
he'd just think that was right
just
come on this way
it was unlocked it never is
[Music]
come on
come on get away from me
[Music]
um
foreign
[Music]
the sea
if you're thirsty come and drink
i'm very thirsty could i
would you mind going away while i drink
sound of that water's driving me frantic
will you promise not to do anything to
me i will make
no promise you mean i'm to trust you
do you eat girls i've swallowed up
girls boys women and men
oh dear and i wouldn't dare drink
then you will die
i won't i'll find another stream there
is
no other stream i see
i have to trust you
oh it's the purest water i've ever
tasted
come here
closer
human child where is the boy
but you saw he fell over the cliff and
then floated away sir
how did he come to do that child
he was trying to stop me from falling
sir and why were you so
near the edge i was showing off
sir that is a very good
answer the boy's
safe i've blown him on the winds
all the way to narnia but
your task will be harder because of what
you have done
i didn't know i had a task here the task
for which i
called you and the boy out of your own
world
ah let us go together to the pool
human child and i will tell you what
your task is to be
[Music]
from here is the land of narnia
and in that land lives the ancient king
caspian the king is sad
because he has no prince of his blood to
be king
after him he has nowhere
because his only son was stolen
from him some years ago
no one in lania knows where that young
prince went to
or even if he is still alive
but he is
alive now i lay on you this command
that you seek this lost prince until
either you have found him or
died in the attempt but i wasn't
noticing
i've forgotten what he looks like
already i've never even been here before
how can i i will tell you child
these are the signs by which i will
guide you in your quest
without these signs you can do
nothing so
remember
[Music]
first as soon as the boy used to set
foot in narnia he will see an old and
dear friend
to get help he must greet that friend at
once
[Music]
two you must journey
out of narnia to the north overcoming
all hazards until you come to the ruined
city
of the ancient giants
three you shall find
a writing on a stone in that ruined city
and must do what the writing
tells you to do
four if you ever
find him you will know the lost prince
by this
that he will be the first person you
have met in your travels
will ask you to do something in
my name
in the name of
aslan i see
child perhaps you do not
see as well as you think
repeat to me in order
before signs
yes first we go north too
no first eustis has to recognize his old
friend
then we go north and then sit down
we will say these signs over and over
until you get them right
one as soon as houston sets foot in
nanya
he will see an old and dear
friend as soon as eustis sets foot in
narnia he will see an
old and dear friend very
good and you must say the four
signs to yourself every day morning
and night to keep them alive in your
memory
you'll know how you are to get to narnia
as the boy used to sting
there's no hurry if he sees someone he
knows he's bound to speak to them
there is no time to spare you must go
i made a terrible start here i know i
have
if i hadn't been showing off scrub
wouldn't have fallen he'd have heard all
the signs too
and then if i forgot them he'd remember
them but now child
[Music]
silence
oh
[Music]
oh it's lovely
oh this is amazing
[Music]
the sea where am i going
oh no
[Music]
so
quickly do you see anyone you know so
you've turned up again have you
keep quiet i'm trying to listen oh but
there isn't a moment to lose
don't you see some old friend of yours
here because you've got to go and speak
to him
what are you talking about i've seen the
lion
aslam and he says you've got to aslan
you've seen as
he said the very first person you saw
here in nine you'd be an old friend
you've got to go and speak to him at
once to get the help we need
nobody here i've ever known i don't even
know if this is
narnia but i thought you said you'd been
here before i have but i've never seen
this place
now dry up and let's see what's
happening
yes
[Music]
hello who are you too
my name's scrub
this is paul jillpole
would you mind telling us where we are
in the land of narnia
at the king's castle of cal polymer
is that the king who's just taken ship
too true too true
but who are you there's something
magic about you i saw you arrive
you flew you flew he was sent by aslam
aslan we've been sent to find the lost
prince
first i've heard of it what prince you'd
better speak to the lord regent
at once to whoa
i can't think clearly yet i'm never
myself until the sun goes down
oh there's more there's a lot more aslan
gave me four signs to remember and that
was the first of them
you had to go straight to your old
friend but i tell you
the lord regent trump killed the dwarf
and what is the king's name caspian of
the tenth
whatever's the matter
he was my old friend then we've missed
the first sign
[Music]
two strangers my lord hey what ranges
all i see is two uncommonly grubbing
ankles what do they want my name's jill
a glass called jelf what the girls are
all killed
who killed him nobody's been killed oh
nobody all right all right there's no
need to shout you think i'm deaf
and why go to all this trouble to tell
me nobody's been killed
i'd rather tell him i'm useless my lord
the boy is used us
well if he's useless we don't want him
here
useless you stuff used to it used to
worked
oh wait a minute oh i don't know when i
was a young dwarf
centers and badges and out really talked
none of this muttering a mum when you
get nowadays
i'm thinking more clearly now it must be
getting later
uh don't mention the lost prince i'll
explain later
oh don't worry what to do
no no no master glenn feather if
anything sensible to say take a deep
breath
speak clearly and say it my lord reagent
these two children are from that other
place
beyond the end of the world they've been
sent here by aslan himself
sent by azlan for what purpose to visit
the great court of narnia
so our fame spreads well my dears you're
heartily welcome
and if my poor master the good king had
not set sail this very hour for the
seven isles
i'm sure he would have welcomed you both
too but it would have brought back his
youth to him
but i think it's super time don't you
well my ideas can tell me your business
in chamber tomorrow morning glim feather
see that suitable bit gems and clothing
are provided for our honored guests
oh and glim feather see that they
properly washed
[Music]
do
come in
oh eustis why didn't you come down to
supper
it's just too scrumptious for words did
you feel like it
aren't you hungry i had something in my
room
i wish we'd never come back to this
place but it's beautiful
it's terrible i've forgotten all about
narnia time
time here is different however long we
stay here
as soon as we go back to earth only a
second will have gone by
we'll go back to things just the way
they were to those bullies
wonderful how dry up the point
is years and years
maybe 70 years have gone by here
and caspian who is young like us
is now an old man he's had his old life
and i'm still a child even if i had
recognized him i wouldn't have known
what to have said to him
we've missed the first sign who will
help us now how will we even begin to
find the lost prince oh shut up
anyway what were the other signs the
second one was
oh dear i know
go to the north of narnia the third one
was
and the fourth was uh i'm going to bed
oh you've got to remember those signs
i'll try i'll concentrate i will
remember them
two go to the north
three when you find white
to do
oh mr glenn feather twill
that's to do if you're an earnest about
finding a prince oh we've got to be
i wouldn't care to get on the wrong side
of that lie then you must come with me
tonight
i'll go get the other human you'd better
put on something warm
i'll be back in two twos two
use this use this wake up wake up
come on come but along
eustace i've taken they haven't come
back for you now get aboard
get a boardwalk why be of course
[Music]
are you comfortable oh yes it's so
smooth
don't do that i nearly slid off sorry
just knobbing about having that much
suffering there's nothing more
sustaining
than the last
[Music]
why won't you tell me why is everything
so secret you will know
soon enough all you need to know you are
you're not
for i know you could be kidnapping me
nonsense
really there look out
you please oh no only one thing in the
whole sky and you have to go straight at
it
[Music]
oh don't fall it's a long way down
where are we oh is that you
useless i can't see a thing
can't you look around
who are they what are they
mr glenn feather mr glimmerfeather
used us
to you too of course we're ours
and this my dear humans is a special
emergency meeting
of the great parliament of owls
just a moment there's something i want
to say
first well
time in our world is different and
though king caspian the tenth is an old
man
and i'm only a boy he and i sailed
together
right to the eastern end of the world
that legendary voyage
oh with lord trinion and repeat and all
of them
and you better know right away i am
loyal to caspian
i am the king's man and if this is a
meeting to plot against him
i'll have none of it
bravely spoken human boy but in fact
we're here to talk about you two what
about us
it's simply that if the lord regent
trump in the dwarf
here's you mean to look for the lost
prince he'll put you under lock and key
you mean trumpkin's a traitor caspian
always said he trusted him
oh no trumpkins no traitor but over the
years many of our champions have set out
to look for the lost prince
and not one has ever come back so the
king has decreed
not to have all his bravest narnians
destroyed in the search for his lost son
so now nobody is allowed to go but
surely he'd let me go
once he knew who i was and who sent you
who sent both of us
oh yes the parliament should know that
these young humans
were sent on this noble mission by the
great
aslan himself put the king's away on his
last voyage and trump kim would stick to
the rules he doesn't even take any
notice of us
and everyone knows how wise we owls are
but if we have to wait to persuade the
king how long is he going to be away
if only we knew there is a rumor that
aslan has been seen in the islands
and the king wants to make one more
attempt before he dies to see
aslam face to face to ask his advice
on who is to be king after him now that
he has lost his son
if he goes searching for aslan surely
exactly
there's no telling when he'll be back
but tell us about the lost prince
i think that would best come from our
friend here who remembers all
a natural-born storyteller he is he can
plant the best pictures in your mind
close your eyes
[Music]
some years ago when brilliant son of
caspian was a young knight
he rode out with the queen his mother on
a beautiful may morning
they took no hounds with them but they
were not hunting
but main
[Music]
in the warm path of the day they decided
to rest in a pleasant glade
no one there knew of the terrible
consequences that were to befall them
[Music]
me
ah
by the time prince had reached his
mother one glance told him that physic
in the world would do her good
[Music]
the queen was more vile and prince
really took his mother's death very hard
[Music]
again and again he returned to the north
to kill that vile serpent
but no sign of it did he find
after a month they seem to come over him
a change i so thought caspian's great
friend
lord gerainian
your majesty by my advice you must stop
riding out to seek that evil serpent
it is too dangerous a thing sire to do
alone serpent
my good friend dreamy and i have not
thought of the creature these seven days
why go you to the woods tire
because i've seen there the most
beautiful thing that was ever made
prince let me ride out with you tomorrow
that i too may see what this fair thing
is
[Music]
but my lord might come so often to this
of all places
you will see
um
[Music]
curse you trinion you frighten the lady
away
let us go my lord from this accursed
place
[Music]
cursed no longer to me
then came the fateful day when prince
rillian returned again to that
[Music]
you have searched for the prince for
days
i fear i may never see my son again
o my lord king slay me
speedily as a great traitor
for by my silence i have destroyed your
son
he has gone to the place of the queen's
destruction
has himself disappeared
i have lost my queen and my son
should i lose my friend too
and the old king has lived in sadness
ever since but no one has ever
discovered what happened to the young
prince well i bet the serpent and that
woman were one in the sea
but we don't think she killed the prince
for no bones were ever found
we know she didn't aslan himself told me
the prince is still alive but that
almost makes it worse
for it means the evil woman must have
some use for him
and surely some deep scheme against
earlier
long long ago a white witch came out to
the north and bound over our lands in
snow and ice for a hundred years
this could be some of the same crew and
paul and i have got to find the prince
can you help us any clue you too
we have to go north until we reach the
ruins of a giant city
well can you help oh oh no oh dear city
of giants all very
very sorry and all that that's it's all
[Music]
how do we start
if they must go that way then at least
we can take them as far as the mouse
wiggles
ah they're the ones they know the
northland's best they're the only ones
the only ones who can help
oh come on then i'll take one
oh well as long as it's only as far as
the mask wiggles i'll take the other
[Music]
young human don't rock the boat they
gave me this sword at care caravel
and i don't intend to travel without him
this you idiot you'll fall off
oh no i won't i'm back in narnia and the
air here
i've forgotten how good it is i feel
stronger every minute hold on we go
[Music]
we are here on the lions business
we come in the service of aslan
to you to you
[Music]
ow
what happened is the king dead
has an enemy landed in narnia
i know it's a flood
or maybe dragons it's nothing of the
sort
come on here
[Music]
farewell to you too
too goodbye game feather
goodbye mr owl thank you for everything
thank you
[Music]
i haven't got much to offer you you're
like cold
and hard damp too i shouldn't wonder
don't sleep a wink most likely even if
there isn't a thunderstorm
or a flood where the wigwam doesn't fall
down on top of us all
just have to make the best of it
[Music]
oh
scrub
funny place at least it's dry and warm
it's a wigwam like red indians living
who was he anyway that chap last night
i think much like his hand
looked like a i feel frogs
after sleeping in my clothes i was just
thinking how nice it was not to have to
get dressed
wash i suppose
listen to the birds i wonder where the
thingami's got
to the marsh wiggle
hello that must be him over there
i suppose we better go and speak to him
good morning guests
i say good but it'll probably turn to
rain
or maybe snow or fog
or thunder i dare say you didn't get any
sleep but we did
we had a very restful night ah i see
you're trying to make the best of a bad
job
we had a very restful night excuse me
but we didn't quite catch your name my
name
is puddle glum you're sure to forget it
i was just trying to catch a few eels to
make an eel stew
though i suppose i won't get any and you
wouldn't like it if i do why not
boy it's against reason
that you should like our vittles
all the same if you two could try to
light the fire
no harm in trying though of course the
wood will be wet where shall we light it
where shall we light it ah
you could light it in the wigwam but
then we'd all get smoke in our eyes
oh you could light it outside and then
the rain would come down and put it out
there's my tinderbox except you won't
know how to use it
[Music]
i'm not completely useless
you see you did catch some meals
a dozen of them in fact oh yes but
they'll be very tough you'll see i think
you should tell me your plans
all we want to know is can you really
help us to find prince rillian
well i don't know if you call it help
we're not likely to get very far on a
journey up north not at this time of the
year with winter coming on
but don't let that worry you what with
enemies and
mountains and rivers to cross and losing
our way
and almost nothing to eat and sore feet
we'll hardly notice the weather we
are you coming with us of course i don't
expect i'll ever see the king back in
narnia now that he set off for foreign
parts
and he had a nasty cough when he left
and trumpkins old
and failing fast and we'll have a bad
harvest after this drought
dry summer and i shouldn't wonder if
some enemy attacked the country so all
in all
you may as well come with us but where
should we start
we've got to start by finding the ruined
city of the giants
aslan said so got to start by finding it
have we
yes aren't we allowed to start by
looking for it
that's what i meant of course and then
when we found it we can
oh yes isn't the stew ready yet
ready it might be
thank you
but you're not going to like it
delicious it's the best you i've ever
tasted in my life
might taste all right but beware of
collywobbles in the tummy
food for wiggles is poison
for humans
where were we doesn't anybody know where
the worm city is
i don't know about anybody but if i were
looking for the ruined city i wouldn't
start from here
where would you start from it is more
but can't we get to weddings more from
here
yes of course see those hills and that
bit of a cliff over there where the
dragons flying bound to meet some of
those brutes
well those hills are the beginnings of
ettinsburg but
there's a river between it and us no
bridges of course
perhaps on ettin's more we shall meet
people who can tell us the way
me people oh yes you're right about that
what sort of people live there
oh i suppose they're all right in their
own way
yes what kind of people live there kind
is one thing they're not you'll see now
look here
i don't believe the whole thing could be
half as bad as you're making out
just as the beds in the wigwam were hard
well the firewood was wet
i don't think islam would ever have sent
us here if there was as little chances
all that that's it boy
put a brave face on it all we have to
worry about is our tempers
and all our hard times are going to have
to go through together we'll do to lose
our tempers you know
otherwise we'll finish up knifing each
other
i shouldn't wonder well if you think
it's as useless as all that
you can stay behind paul and i will go
alone don't be such an idiot scrub
no no i'm coming sure i'm certain
i'm not going to lose an opportunity
like this it'll do me good
you see
the other marsh wiggles think i'm too
flighty
flighty i don't take life seriously
enough
they think i'm too full of bobbins
and bounce life's not all eel pie and
fricassee frogs they say
i need something to to to sober me down
so a job like this a journey up north
looking for a prince
who probably won't be there by way of a
ruined city that nobody's ever seen
just a thing if that doesn't steady a
chap
what will i shouldn't eat any more of
that if i were you poisoned for humans
i won't have any more thank you problem
not because i think it will do me any
harm
but because i've had enough already and
i really couldn't eat another thing
all right let's get ready we need bacon
what's left of the stew not much i'm
afraid and biscuits weapons
you have a sword i have a sword and you
and i boy will have a bow and
arrows pole can carry a knife i don't
see why i shouldn't have a bow and
arrows too
what's the matter you'll have a knife i
don't want a knife i want a bow and
arrow no stop complaining you'll have a
knife i'm not complaining i want a phone
look there's only two bows in arrows
there's no difference between you and me
ah quarreling already
that's what happens on adventures right
let's get packed and then
we're off
[Music]
see no bridge
of course there's no bridge i'm sure
we'll be able to cross this on foot
[Music]
see that wasn't difficult at all that
looks the best way out
no the giants live up there giant
i thought the owls would have told you
cheer up po some giants and nani are
friendly
are these at peace or war at peace
officially
but they were badly beaten in several
savage battles and now they have to pay
tribute
makes them rather irritable i don't like
the sound of irritable giants
oh come on
[Music]
i think i might enjoy adventures after
all we haven't had any yet
[Music]
maybe if we keep very quiet it'll go
away
no
[Music]
i knew he wouldn't hurt us how did you
know
i know a thing or two about dragons yes
but you don't know everything
but now we can move on in peace
when we heard about the ruined city i
think we imagined that
the giants were dead oh no that's a long
way ahead
the giant tibetans more are a different
race and very much alive
we seem to be getting closer to that
gorge yes we are i shouldn't wonder
funny rocks hmm if you came along here
when it was half dark
you might really believe those piles of
rocks were giant no
no
look there you can almost believe
that thing on top is a those things
sticking out on either side could be
one of those rocks hits us
[Music]
they're not aiming at us
that's what they're trying to hit
[Music]
i hate those horrible feet
i shouldn't wonder if we don't have snow
soon
they were sure to get lost
[Music]
best look on the brights
back to back that's how to keep each
other warm
whose back will you lie against paddle
plum
my own
it's still jolly cold i know how you can
make yourself feel warmer
how by thinking about how much colder
it'll be when you go
further north
it doesn't work
what are you muttering about the signs
i'm saying the signs
two journey north until you come to the
ruined city of the giants
i bet you don't remember three you're
the one who had to remember them
not fair puddle glove is that fair
[Music]
when you find writing on a stone do what
that writing tells you to do what that
writing tells you to do
do what that writing tells you today
[Music]
this is really the only way to climb all
the way down there and all the way up
the other side
can't do that it's too
dangerous oh there is a bright side if
we break our necks getting down a cliff
at least we won't have to worry about
being
drowned in the a giants bridge
could be a trap it could be a trap
you've got to look out for enchantment
in a place like this
that could just turn to mist and melt
away
just when we're out in the middle of it
there'll be such a wet blanket
why shouldn't it be a proper bridge do
you think any of the giants we've met
would have had the brains to build a
bridge like that
but it could have been built by really
clever giant what
clever giants in fact the very kind
we're looking for
that would mean we're on the right track
the old bridge leading to the old city
that's a real brainwave pole it must be
that
paddlegram
[Music]
we struggled up that slope
these steps are a bit steep
[Music]
i'll tell you something i know if we
break our necks sleeping backwards we
won't break from sleeping down the other
side
yes oh come on
[Music]
wow
you're right
[Music]
where are we now puddleglum 18's moore's
behind us
we face the great northern plain ahead
someone coming now be
careful
anybody we meet in this place is likely
to be an enemy
and we mustn't let them think we're
afraid
and whatever you do don't tell them
anything
at least they're not
my giants day to you travelers
some of you are very young pilgrims to
be walking this rough waste
we're looking for the ruined city of the
giant
the ruined city that is a strange place
to be seeking
what will you do if you find it begging
your pardon man
we don't know you uh or your friend your
silent friend and uh
we'd rather uh we'd rather not discuss
our business
with strangers do you think we'll have a
little rain soon
[Laughter]
well children you have a wise
solemn guide with you
and i think none the worse for him for
keeping his own
counsel but i shall be
free with mine i have often heard of the
giant city ruins
but have never met anyone who would tell
me the way to it
but this road
leads eventually to the castle at
harfang
and in harfang you will find the
gentle giants who are as mild
civil prudent and courteous
as the giants of ettins moore are
foolish
savage and stupid and shall we there
hear tidings of the city ruiners
i know not but certainly you will find
good lodgings and many hosts there you
shall have
hot steaming baths and soft beds
and the baked and the sweet will be on
your table
four times a day think of sleeping in a
bed again
hot baths do you think they'll ask us to
stay
we don't know them you see only tell
them the chi
of the greek turtle salutes them
and has sent them to fair southern
children
for the autumn feast that's really kind
of you thank you thank you very much
but have a care on whatever day you
reach harfang
come not to the door too late for they
shut their gates a few hours
afternoon and open to none once they
have drawn the boat
fare thee well and i mean that children
may you farewell
what a lovely horse beautiful green
dress
carbon
[Music]
i'd give a good deal to know where she
came from
wish he's going to up to no good i
shouldn't wonder
i thought she was super i hope he's half
fang facing before
all the same i wish we knew a bit more
about her
i wanted to ask her all about herself
but how could i when you wouldn't tell
her
anything about us yes and why were you
so unpleasant to them
then i only saw one didn't you see the
night
i saw a suit of armor why didn't he
speak expect he was shy
i wonder what you'd really see if you
lifted up the visor of that helmet and
looked inside
i'll hang it all what else could be
inside except a man
a skeleton or maybe nothing at all or
nothing you could see
invisible huddle glam you do have the
most horrible ideas
you're always expecting the worst and
you're always wrong
let's think about those gentle giants
get as quickly as we can to half hour
i don't think we should go to and not
safe oh really
besides i don't know what a gentle giant
is and aslan signs made no mention of
staying with giants gentle or otherwise
now look here
we're sick of the wind and the rain and
sleeping on cold hard earth
we want to enjoy a bit of warmth and
comfort
now we know you're supposed to be our
guide but if you won't come with us then
we'll have to we'll
well then we will go to our fang
but on one condition
you must both give me an absolute
promise that you won't tell the giants
that we come from narnia
and you definitely won't tell anyone
we're looking for prince rylian
all right we agree promise
all right all right we promise
both of you
both of us promise
[Music]
lord
so
[Applause]
[Music]
oh yes wouldn't be too sure it's midday
they'll be closing the city gates soon
we've got to get there first hurry
[Music]
it's so cold come on paddle glam
nearly
[Music]
i'm perfectly all right thank you but
you'll have to help me out
wait a sec it's not just a home it's too
regular
kind of trench or a lane i'm running due
north
if it's a sort of road we'll be out of
the wind at least i'm out
of the wind what happens further on i'll
have a look
you be careful pole might lead to a
dragon's den
and remember it's giant country
it'll be full of giant worms or giant
beetles i'll be bound
where does that go to nowhere mark
what do you mean nowhere much she's in
the dead funk
i'll have a look steady boy
[Music]
another one
nothing
[Music]
but what a weird place why build
trenches that lead nowhere
no idea come on we're later ready
[Music]
what signs are we supposed to be after
now oh
something about someone saying aslan's
name i'm too cold to give a recitation
here
that's not the next one did nazlan's
name come later
got the signs mixed up i shouldn't
wonder haven't you noticed how
how regular some of these shapes are
something in the signs i shouldn't
wonder
whenever you say that it means something
gloomy so please stop
is this the time for stopping to admire
the view
for goodness sake let's get on it's
getting dark i think we should think of
making camp here
look
[Music]
we must get there in time we must we
must
die if we shut out is where the light is
well it's not exactly come on
not yet
hurry hurry paddle glam steady leave
this to me
whatever you do don't look frightened
we've done the silliest thing in the
world coming here to talk
but now that we are here we must put a
bone face on
that it may be wet blanket he certainly
has plenty of plaque hand cheek
oh there porter guests
seeking lodgings for the night
and remember don't look frightened
what kind of creature do you call
yourself i'm a marsh wiggle
please sir we are two southern children
and this is mr puddle plum and the lady
of the green turtle salutes the king of
the gentle giants
and she sent us to your autumn feast if
it's convenient that is
well that's different that is the autumn
feast
[Laughter]
well you best come into the lodge while
i'm sending word to his majesty
blue faces i didn't know they were that
color
i don't care for it myself but i dare
say you look quite nice to each other
our faces are only blue with cold
we're not this color really you best
come in then and get warm
come in come in your little shrimps
[Music]
come on then come on in that's it
go on get yourselves by the fire get
yourselves warm that's
it
[Laughter]
now they're night you run over to the
house with this message
please we're very hungry you'll get your
whittled soon enough
don't you worry now then froggy
i think you look as if you need cheering
up
here we are that's a bit heavy for you
a cup or a glass would drown you
i know here we are
smells all right
tastes alright too but then it might at
the first sip
there'll be something nasty at the
bottom i shouldn't wonder
[Laughter]
that'll be a tendency
if i suddenly
curl up or burst into flames
oh i turn into a marsh wiggle
or a lizard you'll know not to accept
anything
they offer
[Laughter]
why froggy you're a man do you see him
put it away
not a man not a frog
a marsh wiggle
[Laughter]
let's go to the front room at once
respectable
marsh wiggle respectable very
[Laughter]
show them the way that you're good
that's for froggy there
i think you better carry him he's had a
drop or two more that's good for him
pull me up put me up put me down
[Music]
oh
if you please sire the lady of the green
turtle
salutes you by us
and said you'd like to have us for your
autumn feast
hmm well good little children
quite excellent children indeed
welcome to our give me your hair
what is that respecter diggle oh
the horrid thing it's alive
he's all right really your majesty
you'll get to like him once you know him
knew him that thing
oh the poor little child out in the snow
all day
take them away give them food and drink
and baths
give her lollipops give her dolls and
faucets and comforts and lullabies
and lovely cuddly toys
i'm not that little now little girl
don't cry or you won't be good for
anything when the feast
[Music]
comes
sweet little things
now you've had a good dinner a lovely
hot bath
you should sleep like a trout my poppet
and when you wake tomorrow your clothes
will be washed
ironed and all laid out with everything
a sweet little girl could ever want to
play with
no
[Music]
no tell me the signs
child no tell me a sign
[Music]
i must remember this
you'll know what happens if you cannot
remember tell me
the signs besides you won't know how to
find prince really
ever get back to our own world we'll be
stranded here
please forgive me please forgive me
i'm so sorry please please forgive me
[Music]
know what happens if you cannot remember
beside me
[Music]
peace
i'll try to remember i will
[Music]
promise
polio awake come on in
good morning here's pretty puppets
friends come to play with her
there you are dears
and there you are my pretty little one
no need to tell you to be good because
you're such a sweet little thing
in fact so good it almost seems
i slept and slept i feel so much better
do you
i do but puddle gum has a hangover
i mean a headache look a window seat
we'll be able to see right out
[Music]
we can't have done it again
trim tazzan came and was terribly angry
with me because i hadn't remembered the
signs
look look they were the words
under me under me
what can that mean under me
ruined city under me
the second and third signs muffed
that's the rune city all right we must
have walked right over
it in the snowstorm it's my fault
i've given up repeating the signs i've
been thinking about them i could have
seen it was a sitting
even in all that snow i'm worse i did
see
or partly i had a feeling we ought to
stop
the truth is you were so keen on getting
to this place
ever since we met that woman with black
knight
nearly forgotten about prince william
i shouldn't wonder if that isn't exactly
what she
intended what i don't understand is how
could we miss anything as big and clear
as those letters
we didn't you fell into it
into the e of me that was the trench
with its three side passages
it's clear that the green lady
making you think of hot food and hot
water
was to make you forget about everything
else
aslan was right to be angry with me i
should have remembered the signs
what are they what are they
hang on you told them to me
i ought to be able to remember them
first journey north
well we've done that
it's my fault it's all my fault
to journey north until you come
to the ruined city of the ancient giants
three when you find writing on a stone
do what the writing tells you to do oh
but
he always goes just when i want him to
explain
well the writing says under me
it doesn't make much sense yes it does
though
it means that we've got to look for
prince william
under that ruined city but how
that's another question well we should
just have to go back i suppose
if we can see the word city from here it
can't be far
no point in hanging around for the
blessed autumn feast let's go now
haven't you had any breakfast oh yes
why we're trapped in here
oh come down scrub you're never going to
manage it
anyway do you think the giants really
meant to make a separatist
well whether they did or not that's what
we are
we'll never get out of here i shouldn't
wonder
except we don't know if we are there
prisoners
it's not their fault that everything's
too big for us
the important thing is to have a
strategy
if we do get out of here what do we do
next get back to the ruins stupid
just a minute ago said so we have to get
out of half fang
first well this clue we won't escape by
night
once we're in our rooms and the doors
shut we can't get out
and if we try to escape in daylight
we'll be seen oh dear
afternoon could still be the best time
when they're dozy after their midday
meal
good idea paul above all
we must be merry and bright
you two youngsters are not always in
high spirits you know you must watch me
i'll be ever so merry merry and
frolickson
do you think i'm a funny fellow already
in there you know you two thought i was
rather tipsy last night didn't you
no oh yes you did oh no
well i do assure you it was most of it
was that put on i thought it might come
in
handy anyway we must appear to be happy
here so the giants won't suspect
that we're plotting to escape and we
better keep our eyes open
and learn as much as we can about this
place and how we are to escape from it
that is if we ever do escape
now my poppet you must come and see the
king and queen and all the corpse
setting out on the hunt
oh it's such a pretty sight come along
come along
[Music]
now come along come along seems we're
not prisoners by day anyway
oh they're really friendly maybe we've
nothing to fear after all
can you imagine any horses big enough to
carry that lot i can't imagine that
she's going to queen around the palace
all day what
oh chances he's being merry and bright
you're going to your act
oh your majesty you're not going away
are you
you will be back soon but of course my
dear
we must be here for the orton feast
tomorrow night
we shall be back this evening we're so
longing for tomorrow night
and we do love being here
we do love being here and while you're
out we may run over the whole castle and
see everything man
we so say yes and we may come to the
feast
oh you'll be there my dear
onwards
[Music]
now i've worked to do my puppets i hope
you can amuse yourselves
with the queen's permission we're going
to explore the castle
why of course you must feel at home
little ones for the short time you're
with us they
are so sweet at that age it does seem
such a pity
[Music]
uh
oh you are good oh thank you everyone's
so nice
just doing our job dear i can hardly
wait for the feast
i wonder what i should wear i will be
allowed to stay up for it won't i
you will you certainly will i wish it
was tomorrow night already
i do hope the time goes quickly
poor little things
what is happening
[Music]
are you preparing for the feast tomorrow
night we are
young man how exciting
what's that it smells lovely may i try
it
why not you're a growing child we must
fatten you up
that's useful to know why
you could slip straight out without
having to cross the courtyard
come on paddle gum
it's delicious it's going to be a
wonderful feast i am looking forward to
it
now that's enough young lady otherwise
you'll spoil your lunch
[Music]
i've never tasted venison before isn't
it scrumptious
all right paul you don't have to overdo
it with us she's very good
they all love her i've tried to be
friendly but
uh well girls always do that sort of
thing better than boys
even boys do it better than marshall
there we are
another nice tender halter venison boy
that stag was lying then when he was
caught he said don't kill me
you won't enjoy me i'm terribly tough
not another bite we've been eating a
talking but it's awful to think animals
being killed at all for us to eat
i suppose to them if the animals here do
oh dear
she doesn't understand you've never
lived here before paul
some of my closest friends were talking
animals
i suppose so but we have to eat
we brought down the anger of aslan
that's what comes of not attending the
signs
i'm not too keen on those gentle giants
we've got to make our break this
[Music]
come afternoon hurry up with those
turkeys i'm not so sure afternoon is the
best time
but it is
if we're seen in the daylight we can
always say we're out for a walk which
they wouldn't believe if they found us
getting out at night
don't worry paul we'll manage leave that
hatch door open
so the cat can go in and out poor thing
well that's that done then
the kettle's in its place it'll make a
nice little cup of tea
later first i shall have a little sit
down
i might even have 40 winks
as long as that hunting party doesn't
come back too soon wanting this and that
when do they usually come back there's
no telling with them
oh do be quiet and sit down for a bit
dearies
[Music]
let's make a dash for it
i can't stand this
[Music]
mallard this delicious bird can be
cooked in a variety of ways
a giant cookbook i wonder what giants
eat
man this elegant little biped
has long been valued as a delicacy it
forms a traditional part of the autumn
feast and is served between the fish in
the joint
eustace paddle cannot be quick
oh mark's wiggle
some authorities think this animal unfit
for giants consumption because of its
stringy consistency and muddy flavor
oh is that nice is that nice i would
have
what i'm gonna taste very nice
so
the moment we look like people running
away we're done
what's that it's them keep walking keep
walking
release
[Music]
oh
oh join hands if i could find anyone's
hand
or
we're all linked up slowly now
step by step there'll be a mortal danger
in here i shouldn't wonder what
dragons and invisible rivers and
who knows
[Music]
oh
are you here oh say you are
i don't want to be alone down here in
the dark
i'm here so am i
if you're warm we must have fallen
from mine underground we'll never never
get back to the surface
we're in a tomb no paul
what are we to do tell me what are we to
do
i wish i still had my tinder box would
come in handy here
yes where did you have it last i was
trying to remember
i had it when i gave you a real stew i
thought it was when the dog chased us
into the cave
you might be right there oh stop it you
two
difference does it mean where he lost it
he lost it
earth hundreds of feet below the ground
this time i can't see how we're ever
going to get out
i can't see anything i'm terribly
thirsty
so what make you here
creatures of the overworld who is it
who's there i am the warden of the
underworld and with me
stands a band of under earth men fully
armed so
quickly tell me now who you are and what
is your purpose here
in the deep realm well
a band of men sounds very grand but
in this light how do we know whether
you're bluffing or not
you might only have two or one
[Music]
those chaps don't teach me to take a
serious view of life i don't know what
will
did you ever see such sorrowful
countenances shh
so now answer my question why have you
come here to the deep round
we fell down by accident many fall down
and few return
to the sunlit lands make you ready now
to come with me to the queen
of the deep round
what would she want with us i know not
young insolence
her will is not to be questioned but
obeyed
well stand up
match
[Music]
i can't i can't go into there and i
won't you must follow the others
oh you don't understand she hates being
underground
she hates being in dark closed up spaces
like this must go
on i tell you what
i'll go first and and you can hold on to
my heels
and scrub can go behind you and heal the
hole onto your heels and
that way it won't be too bad
i felt just like you do up on that cliff
top when we first came here bro
come on you must try
there is one good thing about being
underground what's that
you don't get any rain
oh
who is that old fellow
that is old father time
who was once a king in overland
now he has sung down into the deep realm
and dreams of all the things that are
done in the world about they say
he will awake when
at the end of the world many sink down
and few return to the sunlit lands
i can't be long now
[Music]
come on
oh
i'm so thirsty i'm
so thirsty don't worry paul
i'm sure we'll find water soon
look water
come on what are you doing stop there
stop stop
we're so tight now we're still aboard oh
hi
is that the person you're taking us to
person hippiest
child she's the queen of all this vast
underwood so creatures of the overworld
go on board move i'm not going anywhere
under her banner
insolence she is the queen
and must be obeyed without question
come
no don't touch me
[Music]
kostov
hmm
[Music]
we'll never get back to our own world
we're buried here as deep as
deep in the earth steady pole but we're
doing very well
don't you remember we were to go under
the ruined city what we have done we
most certainly are under it
and that means we're following aslan's
instructions again
warden uh uh mr warden
my name is malika theron mr warden
have many others have any other smile
land up a top done this trip
many have come down i know and few have
returned to the sunlit land
[Music]
no flavor absolutely no taste at all
well it could be worse at least if they
don't taste of anything they can't taste
terrible
i think they're rather nice
feels like we've been on this boat
forever
so we've been underground forever
i hardly remember what the sun looks
like
um for a bit of blue sky couldn't we
play a game or something to fill up the
time
i can think of a game remembering the
signs
well yes as you said
three was to do what was written in the
stones
and we did we came down here
four
what's four the first and only person on
our trip
to ask us to do something in the name of
aslan
must be obeyed not that we're likely to
meet any such person down here
[Music]
oh
get your hate
okay
[Music]
what is his face where are you taking
us
[Music]
so
let me sink down to the underworld
a few return to the sunlit lands
that light it's our kind of light that's
all blue and dismal
no no i tell you the queen has gone away
and some great affair
the only thing to be done with these top
dwellers is that what is that you up
there old melon
who have you there strangers sir
creatures of the overworld overwhelmers
bring them down to me this instant it's
please your highness to remember that
the queen
pleases my highness principally to be
obeyed
bring them down
[Music]
connect up
welcome over welders welcomed
next day i cried your mercy i've seen
you two children and your strange
governor before
was it not you three that met me on the
borders of ettinsville when i rode there
by my lady's side
you mean you were the black knight who
never spoke
i was and that lady is the queen of this
underworld
what did she think she was doing sending
us off to a castle of giants
to be eaten for dinner we never did her
any harm
how dare you speak son of the queen
insolent
boy
[Music]
prepare yourself for death yeah
he's only a kid do you want to die
instead
not especially but if it's a choice
between
me and a child you better kill me
[Music]
if you boy were not so young a warrior
you and i would have fought on this
but i will hear no word against my
lady's honor
whatever she said to you be assured it
was a good intent
it couldn't have been she must have been
thanks
she's a nose gay of all virtues
but you shall know and love her
hereafter
[Music]
meanwhile
what is your errand in the deep lands
please we are trying to find prince
willian of narnia
[Music]
brilliant narnia
strange names narnia what land is
that i've never heard the name before
must be a thousand leagues from those
parts of the overworld that i know
what a strange fantasy to come searching
for how'd you call him
billion trillion in my ladies realm
to my certain knowledge there's never
been such a man here
we've been told to look for a message on
the stones of the city ruiners
and we saw the words under me
and under it is here more or less you
were the more deceived
my lady could have given you better
counsel had you had the sense to ask her
those words are all that is left of a
longer script from ancient times which
she well remembers expresses this verse
and throneless now i be
[Music]
yet while i lived all earth
you must know that i'm a man under a
most strange affliction
my lady the queen said that none may see
my face
until the bewitchment is broken
my god bring wine and update us food for
my guests
please you'll be seated gentlemen
i am determined to break through to the
overworld
as soon as possible
you must understand my friends
but i know nothing of who i am or who i
was in my past life
i remember no time when i was not
dwelling at the court of this queen
but my thought is
that she brought me hither to save me
from the evil enchantment
an empty cup frog would suffer me to
refill it
queen and i ride sometimes in the
overworld to accustom my eyes to the
sunlight
but i must go with my visor down i may
never speak lest the spell be broken
but what is this evil enchantment
surrender
i know not
only that at a certain time every
evening i become a changed man
i grow in fury and rage
and would kill even my dearest friend if
he came close to me
and that is a spell with all remarks of
a witch upon it but
by her majesty's art i shall be free
from this accursed mask
and the bewitchment the moment she has
made me king of that land
and given me her hand in marriage in the
overworld above
as a matter of interest where is the
queen now
at that very place
[Music]
inspecting the diggings
soon a thin roof of
earth will be broken through
and with her to guide me and a thousand
under earth men at my back
i shall ride forth in arms slay my
enemies chief men and doubtless be their
crowned king
within four and twenty hours big
[Music]
quick working wit for on my honor i'd
never thought of it so before
[Music]
i see your meaning
isn't it comical to think of all of them
going about their business
and never dreaming that under their
peaceful fields and flaws
only a fathom down is a great army about
to break out upon them like a fountain
i don't think it's funny at all you
sound to me as though you'll be a wicked
tyrant what
the little maid a politician
never fear sweet one
i shall rule that land by the council of
my lady
who will then be my queen too
her word will be my law
[Music]
friends
my ow is very near
i'm ashamed that you should see me
yet i dread to be left alone
what is to happen
[Music]
come
a silver chat it's beautiful
beautiful under its enchantment i've
become
furious in rage
[Music]
stay with me in truth none may
be here when the evil enchantment grips
me
none except the queen but as she's away
you
you must stay
[Music]
we'd certainly be happy to
but those guards threatened us
and the moment they see us well
hey guys
go through on the door at least my
private departments and they're awaiting
my committee once my sufferings
[Music]
yes
should we go back to him no
i'd rather not but think a minute
i'm sure that queen's a witch and an
enemy there's a strong
strong smell of danger and magic and
lies
and treason we need to know everything
that's going on
i vote we go back
[Music]
so
ah
[Music]
coming friends
the fit comes and goes and is not yet
fully upon me
make no noise for i told that crying
warden that you were in bed
listen while i am still master of myself
when the fit is upon me
i shall beg and implore you entreat and
threaten you to loosen my bonds
they tell me that that is what i do
i shall call upon you by all that is
most dear and most dreadful but do not
listen to me harden your hearts stop
your ears
for while i am bound you are safe
if once i were up and out of this chair
i'd be transformed into a serpent and
would kill you
never fear we have no desire to do
battle with servants
but be careful there's no knowing what i
will say to catch you off your guard
you promise you swerve whatever i say i
ask you do not release me from my bonds
i should jolly well think not
nevertheless we must be cautious
are we cunning i shouldn't wonder
[Music]
mercy
quick i'm saying now
every night i'm sane and it is the only
time that i am
if only i could get out of this
enchanted chair
my sanity would last i'd be a man again
myself again
but every night they bind me every night
my chance is gone
you're not my enemies please
quickly cut my bonds
please i beseech you
have they told you that if i am released
i shall go berserk and kill you
see by your faces that they have it is a
lie
is it at this hour that i'm in my right
mind
all the rest of the day i am bewitched
you are not witches
you are not underworld men
of your courtesy cut my bonds
i hope they're safe
you have hearts of stone
you look upon a wretched and suffered
almost more than any mortal could bear
the hours are slipping by
save me now
when these hours have passed
i should be witness again
the joy of that most devilish
you take me from a church that may never
come again
someone surely must have said she met
no no i
didn't stayed in the other room until it
was all over
help me help me give me my
sword not on your life
once i am free i shall take such revenge
on this queen and her people
that they'll talk of it for a thousand
years
[Music]
beware beware
all night i did break my buns
the witch was here to stop me you will
not have her to help me tonight
[Music]
free me now and i'm your friend
i'm your mortal enemy house
[Music]
so for all i beg you to set me free
by all fears by all loves
by the bright skies are overlapped
by the great light by iceland himself
[Music]
set me free
oh no oh dear
the sign
it's the sign
no it's the words of the sign
what shall we do would i
really have meant us to to unbind the
savage lunatic
if only we knew i think we do know
aslan didn't tell pole what would happen
if she followed the signs
he simply told her what she had to do
this fellow might be the death of us if
we lose him
but that doesn't let us off following
aslan
signs
[Music]
so
hello
[Music]
lie therein ruined vile engine of
sorcery
lest your mistress should use you upon
another victim
[Music]
what do i see a marsh wiggle
a real live honest gnarly and marsh
wiggle
then you have heard of narnia you may
well believe it for i am reliant
prince of narnia oh your royal highness
oh we've come for no other reason but to
seek and to deliver you
who are my other rescuers i'm eustos
i've heard my father speak of you and
i'm paul jillpo
i owe all three of you a greater debt
than i can ever repay
but tell me my father he is well
he still lives he lives my lord but is
old and frail
excuse me but shouldn't we be going
we must use cunning for that
[Music]
[Applause]
which one of you
three has dead
destroy the silver chad
i did and these my true friends have
helped deliver me
we do it again too
and in this madness
who do you now think you are i am prince
only child of caspian tenth of that name
king of narnia leave us
i had a purpose for you
my prince
have we not planned together that you
will advance at the head of my army
and make myself king of some
unfortunate nation that never did me
wrong murdering their natural lords and
holding their throne for you as a
foreign and bloody tyrant
[Music]
now that i don't know myself i utterly
renounce that plan
as plain villainy
now
will you give us conduct
out of your own
[Music]
hey
um
so
you are prince brilliant of
narnia
i have sometimes heard your lordship say
that name in your
mad ravings in your chair dear prince
you think now that you are well but this
is all part of your sickness and you are
very sick
there is no land named narnia
oh yes there is ma'am
[Music]
i happen to have lived there all my life
indeed
tell me i pray you where that
country is it's up there
i don't know exactly where
up there is there a country hidden
in the roof no it's where you here call
the other world
[Music]
and what or where
pray is this
overworld don't be silly
as if you didn't know it's up above
where you can see the sky and the stars
and the sun
why you've been there yourself we met
you there
i met you
we often meet our friends in strange
places when we dream
but unless all dream alike
you must not ask others to remember it
madam i've already told you grace that i
am the son
of the king of narnia and shalt be king
of
many imagined lands in thy
fancies we've been there too
oh and i suppose thou art
queen of narnia pretty one
i'm nothing of the thought we come from
another world
that other world is all
a dream
there never was any word
[Music]
but mine
you can say what you like and still you
won't make me forget narnia
we'll never see it again i shouldn't
wonder and you may have blotted it out
and made it dark like this for all i
know
but i know i was there how
do you know you were there oh how
how why
i've seen a sky full of stars
and i've seen the sun rise up out of the
sea of a morning
and sink beyond the distant mountains at
night
and i've seen him up in the midday sky
when i couldn't look at him for the
[Music]
brightness
the blessings of islam upon this honest
marsh wiggle
how could we have forgotten it
of course we've all seen the sun sun
the sun is but a children's
story yes
i see now there is no
sun there is no sun there never was
[Music]
there's aslan das what a
pretty name forget
all these childish things
face life here in this real world
your life henceforth is to be here with
me you will do
my work now
to bed with you to sleep
sleep
[Music]
what are you doing filth dare to touch
my fire again
and i'll turn the blood to flames within
my veins
madam there is one thing to say
suppose suppose we have only
dreamed and made up these things like
sun
sky stars and moon and aslan himself
in that case it seems to me
that the made up things are a good deal
better than the real ones
and if this black pit of a kingdom
is the best you can make then it's a
poor world
and we four can make a dream world
to lick your real one hollow
how dare you threaten me
as for me i shall live like a narnian
even if there isn't any narnia so thank
you very much for supper
we're going to leave your court at once
and make our way across your great
darkness to search for our land above
well said
[Music]
three
gentlemen i thank you
i am avenged
for the serpent that killed my royal
mother was undoubtedly the green lady
i think all this time
i've been the slave of my mother's
murderer
last time free we're not out of here yet
it won't be easy to escape you know now
it won't be easy
we'll probably be killed in the attempt
[Music]
oh i know exactly how to escape this
world
you know how we must make for the new
outlets being dug for the witches
planned invasion of the overworld
how close are they to breaking through a
matter of a few feet of earth
dead with all haste mates your highness
a noise they make
i've never heard one of
[Music]
it's the them of her world
[Applause]
[Music]
just in case there's no no one an eye
ahead of us
[Music]
all the queen's goodbye
[Applause]
[Music]
uh
you've had time to tell me little of my
country and my father what is his voyage
he's gone upon
in caspia in the southeast to the far
lands we explored
together when he was very young time is
different in our world brilliant
to me it's only a matter of months ago
but to him a lifetime
what is the object of his voyage only he
said
to see again the places of his youth but
many believe he hoped to meet aslan
to ask who could be the next king of
narnia in case
you never expected to see me again
you're right friend wiggle we must get
home
oh look seaming's getting lower
it's the diggings
bye now
follow me
[Music]
it's not rock it's earth
we can dig our way through what if
there's anything to dig to
is it daylight at least look
[Music]
something might have
that's bad that's very bad
[Music]
it is the prince it is
i'm home
[Music]
i've news for you you want to join
prince william
he has gone to care paravel
to meet his father the old king
whose ship arrives today
[Music]
well mates off you go
goodbye puddleglum sorry i ever called
you a wet blanket
so am i you've been the best friend in
the world
i hope we meet again not much chance of
that
i don't think i'll ever see my old
wigwam again either
i'm sure they've been floods and attacks
by dragons when i've been away
oh hum such his life you're a regular
old humbuck
he always seems miserable as a funeral
but i believe you're perfectly happy
and he says he's afraid of everything
when really he's as brave as a lion
[Music]
bye bye
so
[Music]
homicide king of narnia
oh aslan i'm sorry for the mess we made
of things
i forgot the signs and then and we
nearly got eaten by giants
and silence
i'm not here to scold you've done well
the work i sent you to do in nanya
please may we go home now
i have come to bring you home
[Music]
son of adam go into that thicket and
pluck the thorn that you will find there
bring it to me
[Music]
drive it into my pool must i
you must
[Music]
we saw him with our own eyes yes
he has died most people have
you know even i
have i can see what's bothering you
i'm no ghost if i appeared in narnia
i suppose i'd be a ghost but here
in aslan's country aslan
can we stay no time
when you meet here again then you will
have come
to stay now you must go back to your own
world
but we want to see you again and you
shall shine
you mean sir you are there too
in our world i am
but there i have another name
you must learn to know me by that name
that was the very reason you were
brought to narnia
that by knowing me here a little
you may know me better
aslan i have always wanted to have
just a glimpse of their world
is that wrong you cannot want wrong
things now that you have died my son
you shall see their world for a few
minutes of their
time now
draw your swords but use only the flats
not the blade but it is cowards
and children not warriors you go to
[Music]
fight
back back
[Music]
you must say goodbye caspian
bye aslan goodbye
goodbye goodbye
[Music]
my
you